愛德華·諾頓
美國X檔案
德瑞
Derek.
- 偷窺狂! 丹!  - 媽的! 你想幹嘛?
- Fucking pervert   Dan. - Jesus   what the fuck are you thinking?
外面有個黑人砸破你車 想要搶走
There's a black guy outside. He's breaking into your car.
- 來多久了? - 不知道
- How long's he been there? - I don't know.
- 怎麼了? - 別吵 幾個?
- What's going on? - Not right now   honey. How many?
- 幾個人 丹尼? - 大概一個
- Danny   how many? - One   I think.
- 有家夥? - 什麼意思?
- Is he strapped? - Huh?
- 他有槍嗎? - 我哪知道?
- Does he have a fucking gun   Danny? - Man   l don't fucking know.
等等 怎麼回事?
Wait a second. What the fuck is going on   Derek?
- 待在這 別亂跑 - 天啊
- Stay right here and be quiet. - Jesus.
- 待在這 - 德瑞 等一下
- Stay right here. - Wait a second   Derek. Wait.
德瑞
Derek.
他們就在附近
They're right here.
我對他沒意見
I don't have a personal problem with him   okay?
別低估我的常識
Don't insult my inteillgence   Murray.
你討厭他 我也知原因
You hate this chiId and l think I know why.
我跟他媽約過幾次會
I went out with his mother a few times.
三年前的事了 其他沒了
That was three years ago. It was nothing.
沒了? 是嗎?
Nothing. Really? Hmm.
那報告簡直胡扯 (我的奮斗)
That paper   Bob   it's a travesty.
辨稱希特勒是民權英雄?
Arguing for Hitler as a civil-rights hero?
你該訂範圍
You've gotta draw the line.
你自找的麻煩
Murray   you actually did this to yourself.
叫他們寫任何一本...
You told them they could do a report on any book...
...爭取民權的讀書心得 用直白語言
...that related to the struggle for civil rights. In plain English.
我知道這孩子有點迷失
I am not disputing the fact that the child is confused
有些不當思想...
and harbors some sick ideas...
...但我不想放棄他
...but l am not ready to give up on him yet.
也許是他哥教唆的
His brother probably put him up to it.
跟你保證絕不是他哥
I can guarantee you 100 percent his brother did not put him up to this.
那我不太相信
I find that hard to believe. Whatever.
他是好孩子 也很可憐...
I know he was a good kid and it's a shame what he's been through...
- ...但這太危險了 - 哪埵M險?
- ...but that is dangerous. - Dangerous in what way?
寫得太過火了
Bob   that goes too far.
宣揚種族歧視? 納粹洗腦法?
This racist propaganda   this Mein Kampf psychobabble?
可被灌輸 也可以清醒
He learned this nonsense   Murray   and he can unIearn it too.
我不放棄這孩子
I will not give up on this child yet.
- 我就知是你 - 丹尼 進來
- I knew it was you. - Danny   get in here.
叫你進來 進來!
I said   get in here. Get in here!
5 4 3...
Five   four   three...
...2... 門關上
...two... Shut the door.
要我怎辦 丹尼?
What's it gonna be   Danny?
什麼怎辦?
What's what gonna be?
你做的這個好事
This petty crap you're puillng.
不知道
I don't know.
坐下
Have a seat.
還好嗎?
How you doing?
還好
Fine.
家埵n嗎?
Things at home okay?
好
Yeah.
德瑞早上回家了?
Derek got out this morning   did he not?
對 回來了
Yeah   he did.
他曾是我學生 你知道 是嗎?
He was one of my students. You knew that   right?
榮譽學生 非常聰明
Honors English. He was a brilliant student.
像你一樣 但他交一群腦筋簡單的朋友
Like you. But he hung out with simple-minded fooIs.
也跟你一樣
Also like you.
叫我來是談德瑞?
Look   did you bring me in here to talk about Derek?
他的事跟我無關
Because what happened to him has nothing to do with me.
你現在所作所為都跟他有關
Everything you do right now has something to do with Derek.
這報告我寫得很棒
Look   l followed directions and l wrote an A paper.
"我的奮斗"?
"Mein Kampf"?
- 我該開除你 - 開除啊
- I should expel you. - Go ahead.
- 你以為我怕? - 你會死在街上
- You don't think I could handle it? - No   I think the street would kill you.
這精彩的文宣救不了你
Your rhetoric and your propaganda aren't gonna save you out there.
我們這麼辦
So here's the drill.
現在起我教你曆史
I'm your history teacher from now on.
我們討論當前事件
We will discuss current events.
這門課就叫它...
We will call this class...
...美國曆史X檔案
...American History X.
每天討論一次
We meet once a day.
第一件事
All right   your first assignment is to
明天給我一份新的報告
prepare for me a new paper due tomorrow.
我花了一周看"我的奮斗"  不公平
Oh   come on. lt took me a week to read Mein Kampf. That isn't fair.
- 你要我寫什麼? - 寫你哥
- What do you want me to do it on? - Your brother.
老天 你開玩笑
Oh   God   man. Please tell me you're joking.
我沒開玩笑
No   no   no. I'm not kidding.
我要你分析說明致
I want you to analyze and interpret
使他入獄的所有事件
all the events surrounding Derek's incarceration.
這些事如何影響你...
How these events helped shape your present perspective...
...對當代美國社會的看法
...concerning Iife in contemporary America.
對你的生活
The impact on your life.
對你家人的沖擊
Your family's.
隨你想寫什麼...
Whatever you wanna say   Danny...
...我不會給別人看
...l'll be the only one reading it.
但如果明早...
But if it's not on my desk...
...沒交到我桌上...
...tomorrow morning...
...本校就沒你這人了
...you are a ghost at Venice Beach High.
清楚了嗎?
Are you clear?
清楚了
Yeah   l'm clear.
你告我作弊?
Telling teacher l'm fucking cheating?
是不是?
Is that what's happening?
- 我從不作弊 - 扁他 亨利
- I never cheated in my life. - Beat his motherfucking ass   Henry.
- 我沒告你 - 為什麼出賣我?
- I didn't say anything. - Why you tripping on me?
幹嘛這樣打他?
Why you all kicking him like that?
怎樣?
What's up   man?
你怕什麼? 我不會害你
What you scared for? I ain't gonna do nothing.
怎樣?
What's up?
欠揍啊 婊子? 癟三 你有病啊?
Want some too   bitch? Punk. What's wrong with you?
想死嗎?
You wanna die?
癟三白斬雞
Punk-ass white boy.
算你走運 上課了 他能怎樣
You Iucky I gotta go to class. He ain't gonna do nothing.
看到我的槍就嚇死
He don't wanna see me and the heater.
好在鈴響 不然痛扁那白雞
Lucky the bell rung. I would have clocked that white boy.
媽的癟三
Punk-ass motherfucker.
斃了他
We'd smoke that fooI.
你要保衛自己
You gotta fucking stand up for yourself.
(洛杉磯警局太平洋站)
光頭黨的檔案都在
We got a whole file on skinheads.
- 同一個黨? - 維尼斯幫
- These all part of the same gang? - Venice Beach Gang.
- 我的主角在哪? - 他在做擴展運動
- Where's my buddy? - He's doing a stretch at YA.
- 這家夥就是C.C.(外號)? - 嗯
- This guy C.C.? - Mm-hm.
- 這就是他的檔案? - 嗯 他的檔案就在這
- That him? - Yeah   that's him right there.
今天有一位客人 他來了
This morning we have a guest coming in   and there he is.
- 早安 - 早安
- Morning. - Morning   sir.
- 歡迎你 夥計 - 早安
- Good to see you   pal. - Morning.
這位是西尼博士
Gentlemen   this here is Dr. Bob Sweeney.
他是維尼斯高中校長
He's principal over at Venice Beach High.
從獄中和社區 深入研究幫派活動
He's been doing outreach work with gangs   both in and out of the can.
三年前 當地一個青年 德瑞·溫亞...
Three years ago   a local kid named Derek Vinyard...
...殺害兩名想偷車的克力斯幫
...was sent up for murdering two Crips who were trying to jack his car.
西尼教過溫亞
Bob taught Vinyard back in high school and
非常了解此案
he's followed the case closely.
他是光頭黨?
He was a skinhead   right?
不只如此 他是開曼·亞曆山大手下
He was more like the skinhead. The protU+00E9gU+00E9 of Cameron Alexander.
- 誰? - 開曼·亞曆山大
- Who? - Cameron Alexander.
來  瞄一眼
Here you go. Have a look-see.
開曼·亞曆山大...
Cameron Alexander   well...
...是維尼斯地標
...he's a Venice Beach landmark.
是洛杉磯白人至上主義
He's probably the biggest distributor of white-power
最大的文宣經銷者
literature and videos in L.A. County.
資助激進樂團 寫樂團評論
He promotes white-power bands. He writes reviews.
也寫種族歧視宣傳文章
And   uh   in his spare time this guy even writes hate columns.
有前科嗎?
Does he have a record?
都沒有
He's pretty clean.
一直搜證 但無所獲
Been trying to pin something to him   but it doesn't work.
背後全是他在掌控
Trust me. He's behind all of it.
活動都在他家外面進行
He runs everything out of his house down by the beach.
開曼和溫亞結合後 維尼斯才有了白人幫派
No white gangs in Venice Beach before Cameron Alexander and Derek Vinyard hooked up.
開曼發現德瑞是個人才
AIexander found in Derek his shining prince.
就利用他召集一群...
Essentially   he used Derek to recruit a slew of insecure...
...沒安全感 易受影響的孩子
...frustrated and impressionable kids.
溫亞有很重的包袱...
This kid Vinyard   well   he's got a lot of baggage...
...在這卷NBC帶子 可以看得出
...as you'll see in this tape that we've gotten courtesy of NBC.
本郡消防員旦尼溫亞...
L.A. County firefighter Dennis Vinyard...
...在康頓區毒窟救火時被槍殺
...was shot and kilied battllng a blaze at a suspected Compton drug den.
記者正在溫亞家...
We're at the Vinyard home right now...
溫亞的大兒子 德瑞 願接受訪問
...and lieutenant Vinyard's oldest son   Derek   has agreed to talk with us.
德瑞 請下來一下好嗎?
Derek   if you could come down here   please   for just a second.
請談談你現在的感覺
Look   I know this is tough   but   um   how do you feel right now?
你說呢 什麼感覺?
How do you think I feel?
- 這是個象征 - 象征 為什麼?
- I think it's typical. - Typical   how?
這國家成了犯罪者天堂 你還指望什麼?
This country's becoming a haven for criminals   so   what do you expect?
像我爸這樣辛勤的人...
Decent   hardworking Americans like my dad...
...被社會寄生蟲掠奪一切
...are getting rubbed out by social parasites.
寄生蟲?
Parasites?
那些黑人 棕色人 黃人
Blacks   browns   yellow   whatever.
我沒搞明白
I don't understand.
你是說他的死跟種族有關?
You're saying your father's murder was race-related?
對 種族問題
Yeah   it's race-related.
不僅僅是犯罪 所有問題都因為種族
Every problem in this country is race-related   not just crime.
移民 愛滋 福利  都是黑人社會...
Immigration   AIDS   welfare. Those are problems of the black community...
...拉丁社會 亞裔社會的問題 不是白人問題
...the Hispanic community   Asian community. Not white problems.
不是因為貧窮?
Aren't those issues that deal more with poverty?
不是 不是環境使然 那是胡扯
No. They're not products of their environments   either. That's crap.
少數民族才不管國家怎樣
Minorities don't give two shits about this country.
他們是來剝削 而非擁抱
They come here to exploit it   not to embrace it.
幾百萬歐洲白人來此發展繁榮
millions of white European-Americans came here and flourished.
已經一世代了 他們怎麼回事?
Within a generation. What the fuck is the matter with these people?
要殺個消防員
They have to go around shooting at firemen.
- 這與你父親的死有何關連?
- What does this have to do with your father?
- 他是執行公務被殺
- My father was murdered doing his job.
去黑人社區滅火...
Putting out a fire in a nigger neighborhood...
...他不去理就好了
...he shouldn't have given a shit about.
殺他的毒販也許還領失業金呢
He got shot by a fucking drug dealer who probably coliects a welfare check.
- 別說了 - 我很遺憾
- That's enough. - I'm sorry.
德瑞溫亞服刑三年多...
Derek Vinyard was released from Chino earlier this morning...
...今早出獄
...after serving three and some-odd years.
我們得持續關心此事
I think this is something we gotta keep an eye on.
萬一他出事...
If something happens to him...
...這媟|很不平靜
...things could get very ugly down by the beach.
低調行事
Just keep it low.
以前維尼斯海灘不是這樣
Venice Beach didn't always look like this.
以前環境很棒
It used to be a great neighborhood.
紅磚道雖坑坑巴巴...
The boardwalk's always been a dump...
...但我們搬來這堮...
...but when my dad moved us out here...
...維尼斯是很適合居住的地方
...Venice was a nice   quiet place to grow up.
幾年後 就完了
Over the years   though   it's just gone to hell.
幫派像瘟疫般
The gangs are like a plague.
他們從英格塢和南中移來...
They moved west from Inglewood and South Central...
...占領了這
...and basically took over.
我沒犯規 你腦子有病?
It ain't fouling you. What's wrong with you?
我操你全家
Fuck all y'all.
我沒時間管這檔子鳥事
I ain't got time for all the bullshit.
我操你全家
Fuck y'all.
- 沒事吧? - 沒事
- You all right? - I'm all right.
你跟我說起過的就是那混蛋嗎?
Yo   is that that fool you was telling me about?
對 是那混蛋
Yeah   that's that motherfucker.
就是他
Yeah   man   that's him.
臭婊子
Bitch-ass motherfucker.
所以德瑞加入門徒幫
That's why Derek started the D.O.C.
他說白人
He said white kids shouldn't have to
在自己社區不該害怕
walk around scared in their own neighborhood.
他一度真把社區奪回來了
For a while there   he really made it like it was ours again.
- 傳球 傳球 - 快 塞斯 堵截
- Throw the ball. Throw the ball. - Come on   Seth. BIock.
柯弟 別老拿著 傳出去
Come on   Curtis. Quit chucking it up. Pass the ball.
- 傳球 - 接球
- Pass that thing. - D up.
- 進攻了 - 快 動起來 動起來
- Here we go. - Come on   let's go. Let's go.
快
Come on.
看那個大猩猩 每次都用打陀螺
Look at this fucking jungle bunny. He does a spin move every time. Every time.
- 你拿不到 - 給我 給我
- You ain't getting shit   motherfucker. - Over here. Over here.
給你 小子!
This one's for you   boy!
- 操你...? - 閉嘴
- Fuck you...? - Stop that.
叫誰小子 混蛋?
Who you calling a boy   motherfucker?
你走運! 我受夠你這猩猩了!
You Iucky motherfucker! I'm through monkeying around with your ass!
你這吃屎的大白豬...
You pale   pastrami-eating   cracker motherfucker...
...賭一百我們會贏
...a hundred bucks say I make you my bitch.
聽見沒?
Hear that?
嫌失業金太多啦 賭了!
He's trying to make ends meet for his cut in welfare. You're fucking on!
- 8比6耶 塞斯 - 沒叫你說話
- It's 8-6   Seth. - When l want your opinion   l'll ask for it.
喂 我不夠 幫個忙
Come on   guys   I can't cover this. Help me out here.
- 你大嘴巴 塞斯 - 我會贏他
- You have a big fucking mouth   Seth. - I can take this nigIet down.
屁! 沒錢賭什麼?
You can't take a shit. The fuck are you thinking?
- 我會贏他 先借我 - 閉嘴
- I will beat him. Give me the money. - Shut up. Shut up.
害我們丟臉 閉嘴!
You're gonna fucking embarrass us. Shut up!
我來處理
I'll take care of this.
這樣吧
I got a bet.
我加入 分數不變
I come in this game right now. Same score
但白人跟黑人比輸贏
but we play black guys against white guys.
混蛋
Motherfucker.
媽的
Oh   shit.
開條件吧 豬頭
Name your price   cracker.
不賭錢 賭這球場
No money. No money. For these courts.
不只今天 是永遠
And not just today. For good.
你們贏 我們就走 若我們贏...
If you win   we will walk away. But if we win...
...不准罵人 打人...
...no bitching   no fighting...
...在眾人面前
...here in front of everybody
你們黑人打包袱滾出這
pack your shit and get your black asses out of here.
幹  跟他賭
Man   fuck that. Take this bet   man.
8比6 我們的球
Eight to six   our ball.
來吧
Let's go.
斷球 斷球
Pick him up. Pick him up.
塞斯 過來防守!
Seth   get back and play some D!
快 塞斯
Come on   Seth.
快 動起來
Come on   let's go.
塞斯 過來防守!
All right. Defense!
好的
All right.
把球傳過來 我沒被人防守
Pass the fucking ball   l was wide open.
媽的!
Damn!
動起來 動起來
Let's go. Let's go   yo. Let's go.
搶球 德瑞!
Pick   pick   Derek!
幹! 攻擊犯規
Bullshit! That's offense.
- 滾你的 他走步 - 想打就放馬來!
- Get out of here. He moved his feet. - If you want to go   I'm ready!
- 別肘擊! - 來打啊?
- Don't throw elbows! - Want to go?
混蛋希特勒迷
Adolf Hitler-wannabe motherfucker? What?
我轟死他!
Kill that motherfucker! Dead!
別氣了 老兄 別氣了
Chill out   bro. Chill out.
- 等等 沒犯規 沒犯規 - 放松
- Wait   it's cool. lt's cool. - Relax.
- 沒事吧? - 沒事 給我水
- You okay? - Yeah. Just give me some water.
- 你該喊犯規 - 不能在比賽關鍵時刻喊
- You gotta call offense on that shit   Der. - Not on game point   Danny.
就便宜那些黑鬼
You can't let niggers get away with that shit.
- 這是比賽關鍵時刻 - 德瑞 痛宰他們
- Honey   it's game point. - Shut them down   Derek. Kick some ass.
看我的
Watch this.
搶球
Get that ball.
傳球 傳球
Pass the ball   baby. Pass the ball.
再見
Bye-bye.
滾出去
Get the fuck off my court.
- 這是我們球場 - 操你 賤人
- This is my house. - Fuck you   bitch.
- 怎麼會? - 我傳啦!
- What happened? - I dropped the ball!
滾出去! 這是我們球場!
Get the fuck out of here! This is my court! Yes!
德瑞不准我們去監獄
Derek wouldn't let us visit him in prison.
他說他會很難過...
He said it would make it too hard for him...
...就算去了 他也不見我們
...and that if we came   he wouldn't see us anyhow.
三年沒他在 正在奇怪...
Three years without him   just wondering...
...今天早上七點...
...and then at 7:00 this morning...
...他出現在門口了
...we picked him up outside the gate.
過來 丹尼
Come on   Danny. Der.
回去的路上 他什麼也沒說
The whole ride back   he didn't say anything.
我想留在家 但他叫我先去上學
l wanted to stay home   but he said   "No   go to school. I'll see you later."
拜托  饒了他吧
Oh   come on. Give the guy a break.
怎麼了? 大了就不想抱我了?
What's the matter? You too big to give me a hug?
沒有
No   man.
你在適應空間 我不煩你
I just know you'll need someone to look after you while you adjust to all this space.
對
Yeah   right.
客廳比以前小了
This place is smaller than the old living room.
- 學校還好嗎? - 還好
- How you doing? How's school? - It's good. It's good.
你得把頭發剃掉
You gotta do something about that hair. That 'do has gotta go.
- 女生喜歡這樣.... - 我不喜歡
- I don't know. The girIs like it   so.... - Well   l don't.
你真是剃的光溜溜
You're keeping it pretty close. All the way down   huh?
是的
Yeah.
我忘了這個
Shit   look   l forgot   man.
- 刺時痛死了 (門徒幫)  - 哪時刺的?
- It hurt like shit while they put it on. - When did you get that?
大約一個月前
I got it about a month ago.
開曼正式介紹我
Cameron made it official.
- 開曼? - 對
- Cameron? - Yeah.
- 他給你刺? - 對
- He put this on you? - Mm-hm. Yeah.
- 喂? - 幹嘛?
- Hello? - What?
請等一下
Hi. Just hang on a second.
德瑞 你的電話
Derek   it's for you.
沒事
Nothing. Nothing.
- 房間有電話嗎? - 有
- There a phone in the back? - Mm-hm.
我去堶控
I'll get it in the back.
我接了
I got it.
喂? 嗨
Yeah? Oh   hey.
什麼?
What?
我眼中放光芒 那些猩猩抖得慌
My eyes have seen the glory of the trampllng at the zoo
血洗黑鬼和有色那一幫
We washed ourselves in niggers' blood And all the mongrels' too
拿起沖鋒槍 猶太人全掃光
We're taking down the ZOG machine Jew by Jew   by Jew
白人勇士上戰場
The white man marches on
你認為是那人指使的?
You think our friend was behind that?
我不在乎了
You know what? I don't even care.
今晚我就搞定
I'm gonna take care of that tonight.
我的甜心 小寶貝
My sweet kid. My baby boy.
拜托 別這樣叫了
God   what's with the love fest   you guys?
(三叉戟除蟲公司)
他會寫 他會寫 我盯著他
No   he'll do it. He'll do it. I'll make sure he does it.
我去開門
I'll get it.
- 我來找人 - 你會卡在門上
- Came to see the man. - Can you fit through the door?
操你!
Fuck you!
- 塞斯 - 怎樣 丹?
- Seth. - What's up   Dan?
你好嗎? 德瑞呢?
How you doing? Where's Derek?
在講電話
He's on the phone.
出來 你這混蛋 溫亞 你在哪?
Come out   you free motherfucker! Vinyard   where the fuck are you?
- 溫亞! - 等等
- Vinyard! - Hang on.
- 給我一分鍾 - 溫亞!
- Give me a minute. - Vinyard!
馬上就好
No   I'll be out in a minute.
我很小心 我將來的計劃如何?
I'm being careful. What am l gonna do?
不能一輩子只待在這屋塈a?
I won't stay in my room the rest of my life.
等等
Hold on.
塞斯來幹嘛?
Hey. Hey. What the fuck is Seth doing here?
你叫他來的?
Did you invite him over?
沒有 他常來
No   he always comes over here.
丹尼 出去一下
All right. Danny   give me a minute.
一分鍾就好
Just give me one minute.
你還在啊 肥艇?
God   are you still here   Goodyear?
說我肥艇 臭民主黨?
You calling me a blimp   you fucking Democrat?
你多久沒見過自己腳了?
When was the last time you were abIe to see your feet?
過來 丹尼
Come in here   Danny.
塞斯
Seth.
晚上去開曼派對嗎?
Hey   man   you going to Cam's party tonight?
達薇娜屁股硬嗎?
Is Davina's ass watertight?
你真有病 塞斯
You're fucking sick   man.
放松點 我問你些問題
All right   relax. Let me ask you a few questions.
沒興趣 我有作業
I'm not in the mood. I got homework to do.
說說你學了什麼 否則轟爛你
Tell me some of the shit you've learned   fuck-ass   before l pistol-whip you.
我相信死亡 毀滅 暴亂 猥褻 貪婪
Okay. l believe in death   destruction   chaos   filth and greed.
別鬼扯了 說我想聽的
Cut the shit   Dan. Come on. Tell me what l wanna hear   asshole.
- 你媽那件事? - 你欠扁啊?
- You mean that shit about your mother? - You wanna get fucking beaten   Danny?
沒叫你開口 達薇娜  閉嘴
I'm not fucking talking to you   Davina. Why don't you shut up?
讓我自己處理 好嗎?
Look   you got to let me do this my own way   all right?
我會搞定
I'll take care of it.
你恨誰 丹尼?
Who do you hate   Danny?
非白種基督教徒我都恨
I hate anyone that isn't white Protestant.
為什麼?
Why?
他們是白人的負擔
They're a burden to the advancement of the white race.
- 有些還好
- Some of them are all right   l guess.
- 沒一個好
- None of them are fucking all right   Danny.
都是寄生蟲 還記得開曼說過:
They're all fucking freeloaders. Remember what Cam said?
"我們不認識他們 也不必認識他們 他們是敵人"
"We don't know them. We don't wanna know them. They're the fucking enemy."
為何討厭他們? 說點正經的
What don't you like about them? And say it with some fucking conviction.
我恨現在黑人吃香了
I hate the fact that it's cool to be black these days.
很好 我恨黑人文化...
Good. l hate this hip-hop...
...侵入白人社區
...fucking influence on white fucking suburbia.
- 很好 - 我恨堤碧夏...
- Good. - And I hate Tabitha Soren...
...和她的擁護者...
...and all her Zionist MTV fucking pigs...
...叫我們和平相處的屁話
...telling us we should get along.
少來那套 希拉堙P克林頓...
Save the rhetorical bullshit   Hillary Rodham Clinton...
...那是不可能的
...because it ain't gonna fucking happen.
那是你說過的最棒的話
That's the best shit I've heard come out of your mouth.
別這樣 我替你難過 丹尼
Danny   no. l feel sorry for you   Danny.
那不是你真心話
I know you don't believe that.
- 閉嘴! - 你才閉嘴!
- Shut up   Davina! - No   you shut the fuck up!
你滾 混蛋 出去
Get out of the house   you piece of shit! Please go.
對客人說這話?
Is that any way to taIk to a guest?
對朋友說這話?
A friend of the family?
- 德瑞根本就討厭你 你還拎不清 - 你又知道了?
- Derek hates you and you don't realize it. - Hey   how do you know who l hate?
帥 活回來了
Fucking A. Back from the dead.
老天有眼
God bless Jesus Christ   man.
你瘦啦 老兄  我都快能抱住你了
I think you lost weight   man. l can get my arms almost all the way around you.
瘦了50幾磅 幹 頭發怎麼變這樣
Fifty fucking pounds   man. Jesus   look at this hair. Holy shit.
我叫他要剃 回來真好
Yeah   I told him it's gotta go. lt's good to have you back.
去拿外套 走吧
Grab your jacket   let's get the fuck out of here.
我先跟他說幾句
All right. l wanna talk to him one second.
聽著...
Look....
Hey   uh   listen...
...你今天在校惹事了?
...did you pull some shit in school today?
- 沒 和平常一樣 - 告訴你 他帥呆了
- No   just the usual. - I'm telling you   man   this kid is awesome.
- 你交"我的奮斗"心得 - 是的
- Did you turn in a paper on Mein Kampf? - Yeah.
- 帥 - 你應該...
- Awesome. - You should've...
- 西尼一定氣炸 - 沒錯
- Sweeney probably shit his pants. - He did   man.
開曼叫你做的? 是他嗎?
Did Cameron put you up to that? Did he tell you to do that?
沒有 我自己覺得好玩 你怎麼知道的?
No   man   I thought it would be cool. How'd you know   though?
- 你怎麼知道的? - 這無關緊要
- How'd you know? - Doesn't matter how I know.
他真夠行
This kid is smart as hell.
西尼打來的?
Was that Sweeney on the phone?
對 他打的
Yeah   Sweeney called.
你跟西尼談論個屁?
What are you talking to Sweeney for?
- 別緊張 - 他完了
- Relax. listen. - He's got to get a fucking life.
- 敢惹毛我 - 西尼是個好老師
- He pisses me off. - Sweeney's a good teacher   all right?
他是專制的黑鬼
Sweeney is a nigger on a power trip   Vinyard.
以前是 現在也是
That's what he was like when we were there.
- 永遠都是 幹那黑鬼! - 塞斯
- And it'll never change. Fuck that nigger! - Hey   Seth.
- 塞斯 走開 - 真的假的?
- Seth   go away. Go away. - What? Are you kidding?
去丹尼房間等 我要和我弟弟談談 很高興見到你
Go wait in Danny's room. I wanna talk to my brother. l'm glad to see you.
- 我馬上來 - 快點 我餓死了
- I'll be there in one minute. - Hurry up. l'm starving.
我說真的....
Come here. Seriously   look....
別理那老粗 你想跟他一樣除蟲 來養活自己嗎
Forget this yahoo. He kills bugs for a living. You don't wanna be like that.
真的 不是開玩笑
I'm serious. lt's not funny.
西尼是好老師 你能從他身上學到很多
Sweeney is a good teacher. You can learn from him.
別搞那套把戲了
So don't fuck it up with small-fry shit like that.
你該很聰明
You got to be smarter than that.
你該看看他叫我寫的那些爛報告
You gotta see the bullshit paper he's making me write.
我知道 他說了 我不管
I know about it. He told me about it. I don't care.
他叫你寫你就寫
Do it. You do anything he tells you to do. l mean it.
別在學校惹禍 別來給我...
I don't want you in trouble in school   trying to impress me...
...混淆視聽 好嗎?
...taking this shit in there   all right?
聽懂沒?
Do you understand what I'm saying?
大概 我以為你會高興
I guess   but l was doing it because l thought you'd be happy.
我不高興
Well   I'm not.
媽的 你聽
Shit. listen to that.
對 越來越嚴重了
Yeah   l know. lt's been getting worse.
好了 別擔心 待會再說
All right   don't worry about it. I'll talk to you about this later.
- 好的 - 等一下
- Okay. - Later.
她咳成那樣 你還當著她面抽煙
She's coughing her lungs out and you're blowing this shit in her face all day.
- 熄掉 - 我熄了
- Put it out. - l'm putting it out.
好 走
All right. Come on.
我跟你說
Hey. Come on   I wanna talk to you.
媽 你還好嗎?
Mommy   are you okay?
你在幹嗎? 把煙熄掉
What are you doing? Put that out.
我才叫他別抽 你自己還抽
I'm yelling at him for blowing smoke and you're here sucking on it.
你回來真好
Nice thing to come home to   huh?
嗯
Yeah.
還好嗎?
You all right?
聽著...
Look...
...你要放輕松 多休息
...you gotta take it easy. You gotta get some rest.
你睡我們房 我們睡沙發
I want you to take Danny's and my room and we'll hit the couch.
- 睡沙發很好 - 不好 太糟糕了
- Couch is fine for now. - No   it's not fine. lt's not. This is terrible.
不能這樣過
We can't live like this.
得離開這
We gotta get out of here.
也帶我去嗎?
Can l go with you?
對 我們全都離開這
Yeah   we all gotta get out of here. That's the point.
我休學 找事做
I could drop out of school and get a job.
不行 絕對不行 你要念完 我來想辦法
No. No   absolutely not. You gotta finish. I'll work something out.
德瑞 出去吃東西吧 我餓扁了
Derek   can we please go eat? I'm fucking starving here.
我管你! 去客廳等!
I don't give a shit! Go wait in the living room!
- 老天 - 叫他出去
- God. - I want him out of my house.
我了解
I know   I know. Look.
他是白癡 一直都是白癡
He's an idiot. He's always been an idiot.
他沒辦法 我去寫作業了
Whatever   dude. He can't help it. I gotta do that paper.
我今晚晚一點去找你
Look   l'm gonna catch up with you later tonight.
別去開曼那 離那婸溶楫
Not at Cameron's   all right? I need you to stay away from there.
- 不是要聚聚嗎? - 相信我 待會我再解釋
- Why? l thought we were gonna hang. - Trust me. I'll explain it later.
別去那派對 好嗎?
I need you to stay away from the party   all right?
- 隨便 - 我是認真的
- Whatever. - Hey   l'm not kidding.
答應我你不會去
Promise me you'll stay away from that party tonight.
我不是14歲了
I'm not fucking 14 anymore   all right?
隨便你
Whatever.
天哪 !
God!
走
Come on   let's go.
- 車停哪? - 後面
- Where are you parked? - Out back.
(美國曆史x檔案)
(丹尼·溫亞著)
(我的哥哥德瑞)
分析說明
肛交分析 說明
大家會認識我 是因為我哥
- 人都在那 - 是的
- Yeah   that's the whole bunch. - Right.
德瑞一下就闖出名號
It didn't take long for Derek to make a name for himself.
開曼知道怎麼用他
And Cameron knew just how to use it.
不待一下嗎?
You sure you don't wanna stick around?
我很想...
You know I'd love to...
...但我得小心點
...but l gotta be careful.
我了解
Yeah   l know.
- 到你家見 - 好
- We'll see you back at the house   then. - Right.
- 好 - 祝你好運
- All right. - Good luck.
他叫得瑞...
He sent Derek to the kids...
...找受挫的孩子
...to the frustrated ones.
不想再被黑人或墨西哥人欺負的孩子
The ones who were sick of getting their asses kicked by black and Mexican gangs.
別當癟三...
Don't just be some punk...
...要就做大哥
...be part of something.
好了 注意聽
All right   let's go. Pull it together.
大家吃他這套 德瑞叫他們幹嘛就幹嘛
And everybody ate it up. They did whatever Derek told them to.
來 我們不是來聊天的
Let's go. Come on   we're not here to fucking sociallze.
- 柯弟 那是什麼? - 別這樣 德瑞
- Curtis   what is that? - Aw   come on   Derek.
黑人才吸大麻 丟掉
Weed is for niggers. Put that away right now.
- 老天 - 你要自重
- Aw   Jesus fucking Christ. - Have a little self-respect.
大家聽好 招子得放亮點
All right   listen up. We need to open our eyes.
今晚有200萬非法移民睡在我們國土上
There's over 2 million iliegal immigrants bedding down in this state tonight.
去年我國花了30億...
This state spent $3 billion last year...
...在這些不該來這堛漱H身上
...on services for people who had no right to be here in the first place.
30億
Three billion dollars.
光是捉這些
Four hundred million dollars just to lock up
移民罪犯關起來就花四億...
a bunch of iliegal immigrant criminals...
...因為規劃署說...
...who only got into this country because the lNS decided...
...防堵這些重罪犯是徒勞的
...it's not worth the effort to screen for convicted felons.
誰在乎? 政府不在乎
Who gives a shit? Our government doesn't give a shit.
邊界是個笑話
Our border policy is a joke.
中南美的人不笑我們才怪
So is anybody surprised that south of the border they're laughing at us?
- 笑我們法律 - 對
- Laughing at our laws. - Yeah.
每晚幾千人沖過邊界...
Every night these parasites stream across the border...
...好像這埵鹵}吃
...like some fucking piU+0148ata exploded.
別笑 !
Don't laugh!
這不好笑 這關系你我生存
There's nothing funny going on here. This is about your life and mine.
勤勞的美國人被耍了...
It's about decent   hardworking Americans falling through the cracks...
...因為政府更在乎...
...and getting the shaft. The government cares about...
...憲法所賦與那些
...the constitutional
非本國公民的權利!
rights of a bunch of people who aren't citizens of this country!
自由女神像寫著: "饑餓 貧窮都交給我"
On the Statue of liberty   it says   "Give me your tired   your hungry   your poor."
現在貧窮的是我們
Well   it's Americans who are tired and hungry and poor.
問題尚未解決前 應停止移民!
And l say until you take care of that   close the fucking book!
因為我們失去了
Because we're losing.
我們失去了追求未來的權力
We're losing our right to pursue our destiny.
我們失去了自由...
We're losing our freedom...
...國家被那群外國人剝削光了
...so that a bunch of fucking foreigners can come in and exploit our country.
這不是遠處發生的事
And this isn't something that's going on far away.
不是遙不可及之地發生的事
This isn't happening in places we can't do anything about it.
就是眼前的事!
It's happening right here!
在你家附近發生著 在你身後的房子媯o生著
Right in our neighborhood. Right in that building hehind you.
那家店以前是亞奇開的
Archie Milier ran that grocery store since we were kids here.
大衛 麥可在那工作
Dave worked there   Mike worked there.
後來韓國人買下 開除他們...
He went under   and now some fucking Korean owns it   who fired these guys...
...雇用非法移民 賺了大錢
...and is making a killing because he hired 40 fucking border-jumpers.
看著這些屁事 都沒人管
I see this shit going on and I don't see anybody doing anything about it.
我非常不爽!
And it fucking pisses me off!
你們放眼看看
So look around you.
這已經不是我們的家園 這堣w成戰場了
This isn't our neighborhood. It's a battlefield.
這堿O戰場 你有兩條路:
We're on a battlefield tonight. Make a decision.
你們就眼睜睜站在一邊...
Are we gonna stand on the sidelines...
...看著自己國家被蹂躪?
...quietly standing there while our country gets raped?
幹
Fuck that.
還是要拼一拼?
Are we gonna ante up and do something?
- 對 去拼! - 對 去拼!
- Fuck   yeah! - Hell   yeah!
當然要拼
You're goddamn right we are.
死過來!
Come here!
你知不知道雇非法移民犯法 亞洲豬?
Don't you know it's against the law to hire border-jumpers   you nip bastard?
我操 我操!
Fuck that! Fuck that!
甜心 別害怕 我不會害你
Sweetheart. No   you don't need this. We're not gonna hurt you.
求你不要!
Please! Please   no!
拉丁賤貨!
You fucking spic!
我想這婊子餓了
You know what? I think this bitch is hungry.
她太臭 來些清潔劑
This bitch stinks. Get me cleaning products.
味道像臭魚爛蝦
Smells like fish and chips and guacamole.
給你的
Here we go.
這樣就對了
Yeah   that's it.
起來!
Get the fuck up!
去死吧!
Get down!
墨西哥萬歲
來點豆子吧 豆人
Have some fucking beans   you goddamn beaner.
- 搶走老子工作 - 你個賤人!
- Take my job. - You donkey bitch!
那邊也來點
Get some of that in there.
- 倒下去 - 顏色很棒
- Throw it on   throw it on. - Hey   that's a great color on you.
你可以幹白人的活了 賤人
You can get a white woman's job   bitch.
- 比幹這爛差事強 - 就是
- A Iittle better than this one   huh? - Yeah.
- 白人 - 你可以升級了
- White. - You can move up in the world   huh?
混蛋!
Asshole!
走了 離開這 全都出去 快!
Let's go. We're out of here. Everybody out. Let's go. Now. Now!
好了 大家走!
All right   let's go! Let's go!
- 快走  - 快走 快走 快走
- Let's go. - Come on   let's go   let's go   let's go.
快走
Let's go.
沒綠卡 別想工作 聽懂沒?
No green card   no fucking work   comprendes?
- 快走 快走! - 走 走
- Come on. Come on! - Go   go   go.
收工了! 快走!
We're fucking done! Come on!
(美國曆史X檔案) (丹尼·溫亞著)
爸死了 事情漸漸平靜了
Dad was gone. But things were almost normal again.
德瑞工作不錯 媽也好多了
Derek had a good job. Mom was starting to live a little.
大家心情都好 沒想到禍事會臨頭
Everyone was feeling so good that we just didn't see it coming.
我們早該想到的
Maybe we should have.
諷刺的是暴動中被毀的店...
The irony is that most of the stores that were destroyed during the riots...
- ...多是黑人的店 - 笨
- ...were owned by black people. - That's stupid   though.
幹嘛砸自己社區的店?
Why trash your own neighborhood?
我就說那是毫無理性
Well   that's my point. It's an irrational act.
那些感覺被社會忽視的人...
It's like an expression of rage by people who feel neglected...
...用這方式表達不滿
...and turned away by the system.
沒錯 就像衛茲那次...
Exactly. I mean   it's like we had in Watts...
...或68年芝加哥暴動那次...
...or the riots in Chicago in '68...
胡扯 我不同意
I don't buy that for a minute.
什麼叫無理性的表達 你是逃避
calling a riot an irrational expression of rage   that's such a cop-out.
他們是差勁的機會主義者 一群人...
It's opportunism at its worst. A bunch of people...
...逮到機會就去搶 僅此而已
...grabbing any excuse they can find to go and loot a store. Nothing more.
這些搶自己社區商店的人...
The fact these people ripped off stores...
...讓其他人對法律...
...in their own communities reflects that these people...
...完全喪失信心
...have no respect for the law.
更別提社區意識或公民義務了
And certainly no concept of community or civic responsibility.
慢著 白人也對會白人施暴
Wait a minute. White people commit crimes against white people too.
但白人不會在全國殺人放火
But they're not offing each other in record numbers all over America.
拜托 看看統計數字
Look at the statistics   for christ sakes.
三分之一黑人男性正接受懲治教化
One in every three black maIes is in some phase of the correctional system.
是巧合嗎 或是那種族有犯罪天分?
Is that a coincidence or do these people have a racial commitment to crime?
不僅如此 他們還很驕傲
Not only that. They're proud of it.
也許是司法制度有偏見
Maybe it says something about prejudice in the judicial system.
你要談犯罪率...
If you wanna taIk about criminal statistics...
...該看看這社會的不公平
...you might wanna take a look at the social inequallties that produce them.
對 我最恨這個
Yap   yap. You know what? That's exactIy what l hate.
因為你每次都指鹿為馬...
Because you're taking one thing and calling it something else...
...強把他們應負的責任淡化掉
...and alieviating the responsibility that these people have for their own actions.
就好像說:
It's like saying:
"不是暴動 是憤怒 不是犯罪 是貧窮"
"It's not a riot   it's rage. It's not crime   it's poverty."
全是鬼扯 法庭也這樣
It's just nonsense. It's bullshit. It's exactly what happened in this trial too.
媒體亂報導 所以大家就只注意那些條子...
Because the media twisted things around so people focused on these cops...
...會不會定罪...
...whether they'd get convicted...
...隆尼金的權利有沒被侵害
...and whether Rodney King's civil rights had been violated.
忽略了隆尼本身
Everybody lost sight of Rodney King himseIf.
他自己承認犯下多起案子
The guy's a multiple felon by his own admission.
他尾巴翹天上 在高速公路開時速120公
He's high as a goddamn kite   driving 120 miles an hour down the highway.
被條子攔下 他攻擊他們
He gets pulied over by a bunch of cops   and he attacks them.
攻擊條子 那是底線 然後他離開了
He attacked police officers. Bottom Iine. And he walked.
一個痞子經過 正好拍下...
And there's some yahoo with a video camera who turned it on halfway through...
...我們就只看到條子打他
...so all we see is them hitting him.
波威和庫恩用警棍打他...
Exactly. Powell and Koon winding up and cracking him with billy clubs...
...布奡迉揖L後腦勺
...and Briseno's kicking him in the back of the skull.
大家就說: "好可憐"
And people are going   "Oh   this poor guy."
他打四個條子
Poor guy who attacked 4 cops.
條子卻要因完全正當的防衛...
And those cops end up on the stand defending themselves...
...上台接受審訊
...for using absoluteIy standard   textbook self-defense procedures.
影帶中不是那樣
I don't think the tape showed that at all.
你反對? 你成了有關當局啦 媽?
You didn't think so? And what   you're an authority   Ma?
你說呢 莫瑞?
Murray   what do you think?
我覺得警察打得很過分
I did think that the police used their clubs rather excessively.
什麼叫過分? 那非常正當
Who are you to say what's excessive? I think it was totally approprlate.
他們的判斷力比你強
They're in a better position to make that call than you are.
社會賦予條子
In fact   we as society   grant cops
那種職權...
a certain amount of authority to make those calls...
...因為我們承認他們的工作很危險
...because we acknowledge that their job is difficult and dangerous.
但不幸的是 太少人尊重那種職權
You know? Unfortunately   very few people   Iike   respect that authority.
你尊重誰啦 三K黨
Look who's talking about respect here   Mr. Junior-KKK.
- 什麼? - 黛薇娜
- What? - Davina.
想念大學就先聽好 黛薇娜
You wanna go to coliege   Davina? You should Iearn to listen.
法律是很爛 我承認那是因為條子職權
I didn't say I respected laws. I acknowledge a cop's authority.
但我更惡心讓那些讓罪犯逍遙在外的法律
I don't respect Iaws that let monkeys like Rodney King on the street.
第二: 我不是那種...
Second   l am not   as you well know...
...沒組織 低級的三K黨員
...a member of a low-rent   disorganized bunch of rednecks like the fucking KKK.
拜托 別胡扯了
Please. So take your head out of your ass.
你根本沒重點
You've gotten off the point.
- 我說的是重點 - 是嗎? 重點在哪?
- I had a point. That wasn't the point. - Do you have one? What is your point?
你想想看
All right   think about this.
那天晚上換做是丹尼在街上...
If Danny had been walking across the street that night...
- ...被隆尼打了...
- ...and Rodney King had plowed into him...
- 別再談隆尼了
- Can we just drop this Rodney King thing?
誰要吃甜點了?
Who would like some dessert?
我們在討論
We're having a discussion.
我們在很認真的討論
We're having a nice discussion   right?
若隆尼喝了酒 嗑了藥...
If Rodney King had been hopped up on Chivas Regal and PCP...
...殺死丹尼 你看法就會不同
...and kilied Danny   you'd sing a different tune.
你我都沒看見他打人
I didn't see him hit anybody and neither did you.
正好他沒殺人
He didn't happen to kill anybody.
- 謝天謝地 - 小聲點 愛莉在睡
- Thank God. - Keep it down   okay? Ally's sleeping.
若他殺了人呢?
If he had   though?
若那猩猩碾死孩子...
Come on   think about it. If that monkey had run some kid over...
...你就會有不同看法了
...everybody would have a different opinion of this matter.
焦點該是隆尼 而不是條子
They'd be focused on Rodney King and not on these officers.
卻說他只是攻擊警察
But instead   he just attacked a few cops.
全國都開始聲援這混蛋
Now all the sudden it's Hands Across America for this total son of a bitch.
太奇怪了
I mean   it blows my mind.
我們迷信...
We're hung up on this notion we have some...
...該幫助黑人這種論調
...obllgation to help the struggllng black man.
讓黑人從曆史的不公中站起來
Cut him some slack until he can overcome these historical injustices.
你們只會說這套
It's crap. This stuff you guys are saying perpetuates it.
什麼自由啦
All this liberal nonsense.
國家已經腐爛了 大家還不知道
Everyone's looking the other way while our country rots from inside out.
林肯130年前解放的黑奴
Christ   Lincoln freed the slaves   what   like   130 years ago?
多少年後卻在結幫搶劫?
How long does it take to get your act together?
猶太人五千年前被迫害
Well   Jews have been persecuted for over 5000 years.
反對反猶太主義是錯的?
Are you saying that it's wrong to feel sensitive about anti-Semitism?
廢話 我站你這邊 寶貝
Forget that. I'm with you. I am with you all the way   baby.
- 都是偽君子 - 真好 又來了
- I'm sick of these liberal hypocrites. - Here we go again. l love this part.
看看黑人警長取代了蓋茲
Well   look at the way that they scapegoated Chief Gates.
他們對黑警長客氣的很?
They'd come down that hard on black Willie Williams?
- 影帶是陷害蓋茲的 - 我先離席 好吧
- No way. The video was a setup. - Jesus Christ. Can I please be excused?
- 好的 - 不准 別打斷
- Yes. - No   you cannot. Don't interrupt.
我講話 你得聽
Excuse me   I was talking. I listened to you.
- 別打斷她 - 你以為你是誰啊?
- Don't interrupt her - Who the hell do you think you are?
- 她在說話 - 你以為你是誰啊?
- She's in the middIe of a point. - Who do you think you are?
- 坐下! - 你去死!
- Sit down! - No. Fuck you!
- 坐下 閉嘴! - 德瑞 冷靜點
- Sit down! Shut up! - Derek   calm down.
- 坐下! - 德瑞 冷靜點
- Sit down! - Derek   calm down.
- 閉嘴! - 別叫他閉嘴!
- Shut up! - Don't tell him to shut up!
- 坐下 - 去你的 走開!
- Sit your ass down! No. - Fuck you   move!
- 坐下 閉嘴! - 別擋路 走開!
- Sit down   shut up! - Get out of my way! Move!
媽的 德瑞 走開!
Goddamn it   Derek   move!
閉嘴 對我女友尊重點
Shut your mouth and give my girlfriend respect.
德瑞 你想證明什麼?
Derek   what are you trying to prove?
馬瑞 滾出我家! 過來 你以為要到哪堨h?
Murray   stay out of it! Come here. Hey. Where do you think you're going?
- 德瑞 放開她! 德瑞 放開她! - 過來!
- Derek   let her go! Derek   let her go! - Come here!
學學禮貌 黛薇娜
You need to learn some fucking manners   Davina.
- 閉上嘴! - 德瑞!
- Shut your fucking mouth! Shut up! - Derek!
住手!
Stop!
她窒息了!
She can't breathe!
放開她!
Let her go!
你道歉嗎?
Are you gonna apologize?
Are you gonna apologize? Are you?
你是混蛋
You're a fucking asshole.
我恨你!
I hate you!
德瑞 你在做什麼? 她是你家人
What are you doing   Derek? This is your family.
對 是我家人 所以不管你...
Right   my family. So you know what? I don't give two shits about you...
...或別人怎麼想 你永遠不會是我們家一份子
...anybody else or what you think. You're not part of it   never will be.
- 這是兩碼事! - 是嗎?
- That has nothing to do with it! - lt doesn't?
你以為我不知你想幹嘛?
You don't think l see what you're doing?
你以為我會眼睜睜看你操我媽?
You think I'll sit here and smile while some kike tries to fuck my mother?
你死心了吧!
It's never gonna happen!
只要我還在 你就別想
Fucking forget it. Not on my watch. Not while I'm in this family.
我就割你鼻子 插你屁眼...
I will fucking cut your ShyIock nose off and stick it up your ass...
...如果你敢的話 過來...
...before I let that happen. Coming in here...
...拿愛猶太 愛黑人那套來毒害我家人!
...and poisoning my family's dinner with your Jewish   nigger-loving   hippie bullshit!
我操你!
Fuck you!
對 快滾
Yeah   walk out.
拜魔教的混蛋!
Asshole-fucking   Cabala-reading motherfucker!
滾離我家!
Get the fuck out of my house!
這意思是: "不歡迎"
You see this? That means "not welcome."
- 我做了什麼? - 你讓我惡心!
- What did l do? - You disgust me!
你讓我惡心! 讓他來家!
You disgust me! Bring him to our table!
打扮成這樣!
Primping your hair and your dress!
- 別碰我! 看你這腔調! - 我造了什麼孽?
- Don't touch me! All tarted up! - What did l do to you?
帶他坐到爸的餐桌前? 你這樣對爸?
How could you bring him to Dad's table? How could you go from Dad to that?
不慚愧嗎?
Aren't you ashamed?
我慚愧生了你這種孩子!
I'm ashamed that you came out of my body!
去找你龜公 去他身邊!
Go run to your fucking kike! Go run to him!
沒關系 我以你為榮 寶貝
It's okay. I'm proud of you   baby.
我很難過 桃莉
I'm so sorry   Doris.
真的很難過
I really am.
- 他迷失了 - 他只是孩子...
- He's gone. - He's just a boy...
...沒爸爸的孩子
...without a father.
桃莉 你不知他的心到哪去了
Doris   you don't know the world your children are living in.
再見
Goodbye.
還好嗎?
Hey. You all right?
- 你這混蛋! - 別這樣 過來!
- Take this   you fucking dick! - Hey   no. No   no   come here!
- 去死! - 冷靜點!
- Fuck you! - Calm down!
- 放手! - 冷靜點!
- Let go of me! - Calm down!
放手 媽的!
Let me go   goddamn it!
- 對不起 - 你去死!
- Sorry. l'm sorry. - Fuck you!
我不會傷你 你知道的
I would never hurt you. You know that.
我不對 失控了
Come on   l screwed up. l lost control.
不是你的錯
It's not you.
對不起
I'm sorry.
我決不會傷害你們
Come on   l'd never hurt you guys. I'd never hurt you.
你知道的 我會為你做任何事
You know that. I'd do anything for you.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
我不信任你 德瑞
I trust you   Derek.
你下床幹嘛?
What are you doing out of bed   huh?
- 要坐飛機? - 是的
- Want a plane ride? - Yeah.
起飛囉
Going for takeoff.
噢 不
Oh   no.
不! 別撞到了!
No   no! Don't crash!
飛到媽那
Gotta go to Mom.
她是瘋狂飛機
She's a crazy filer.
親媽媽
Kiss Mom. Oh   yeah.
- 很燙嗎? - 是胸口熱
- You don't feel too hot? - No   it's in my chest.
- 幹嘛起來? - 我在想...
- What are you up to? - I'm just thinking...
發生的那麼多事情
A lot of that going around.
- 我們怎會變現在這樣 - 媽
- I don't even know how we got here. - Mom.
我都不知道是何時開始讓你們失望
like l let you all down. I don't know when it happened.
媽 沒事了
Mom   it's okay.
- 是嗎? - 是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
這好冷 難怪你生病
It's cold in here. No wonder you're sick.
不是冷 是因為細菌
Don't get sick from cold   you get sick from germs.
不 是因為抽煙
No   you get sick from smoking.
你要戒煙 吸煙對你不好
You gotta quit. It's not good for you.
幹嘛那樣看我?
What are you looking at me like that for?
把你那漂亮頭發留起來吧?
When are you gonna let that beautifuI hair grow back?
等你戒煙那天
The day you quit smoking.
一言為定
Deal.
我送愛莉去睡
I better get Ally to bed.
- 跟媽說晚安 - 嗯
- Say good night to Mom? - Mm-hm.
然後去睡覺覺
Then you have to go to bed. Come on.
- 媽 晚安 - 寶貝 晚安
- Good night   Mama. - Good night   baby.
晚安 媽
Good night   Mom.
(著名光頭黨人被控謀殺)
我不斷回憶那晚的事
I go back to that night again and again in my mind.
想阻止它發生
I try to stop it from happening.
你給我離開這
I want you out of this house.
好的 明早就走
That's fine. I'll be gone in the morning.
他可以跟我住
He can move in with me.
我想著 若我沒去他房塈i訴他...
ln my mind   I imagine what would've happened...
...事情會怎樣
...if I hadn't gone into that room and told him.
丹尼 趴下!
Danny   get down!
丹尼!
No   Danny!
媽咪!
Mommy!
黑鬼 你找錯人了
Nigger   you just fucked with the wrong bull.
- 過來! - 放手!
- Come here! - Get off!
你在球場還沒學乖!
You should've learned your place on the fucking basketball court!
黑鬼永遠學不會!
But you fucking monkeys never get the message!
那車是我爸給我的 混蛋!
My father gave me that truck   you motherfucker!
殺過消防員嗎?
You ever shoot at firemen?
你來殺我家人?
You come here   you shoot at my family?
讓你看看我的厲害
I'm gonna teach you a real lesson   motherfucker.
嘴咬住邊欄
Put your fucking mouth on the curb.
別這樣!
Come on   man!
咬住邊欄! 快咬!
Put it on the curb! Right now!
- 這才對 - 德瑞 不要!
- That's it. - Derek   no!
不要!
No!
說晚安
Now say good night.
混蛋
Fucker.
武器放下! 武器放地上!
Drop your weapon! Put your weapon on the ground!
手舉起來!
Put your hands up!
叫你手舉起來!
I said   get your hands up!
轉過去!
Now turn around!
手放在頭上!
Put your hands behind your head!
給我立刻跪下!
Get down on your knees right now!
沒事
It's all right.
走吧
Let's go.
我沒見過死人
他腦袋被炸開的聲音...
久久揮不去
她不開門?
She ain't gonna open the door?
不知道 有人在那看著我們
I don't know. Someone's there looking at us. Hello?
丹尼 找你的
Danny   it's for you.
我馬上來 (他們說他太過分)
I'll be right there.
(判過失殺人)
(去州監獄服刑)
(若我去作證 會無期徒刑)
開門 丹尼 外面好冷!
Open the door   Danny! It's fucking freezing!
派對一定很贊!
Danny   this party's gonna be sick!
走吧 丹尼!
Come on   Danny!
我去弄點啤酒
I'm gonna go get some beers.
很棒吧 肥塞斯?
Hey   what a party   huh   fat Seth?
混蛋 我不胖! 我是壯
I'm not fat   asshole! I'm husky.
怎樣 塞斯?
What the fuck's up   Seth?
快喝 丹尼 免得你哥看見
Drink up   Danny   before your brother sees you.
幹 他來啦?
Holy fuck. He's here?
- 對 他來咧 - 他來咧
- Yeah   he's here. - He's fucking here.
- 去吻他腳 - 操你 塞斯
- Go pay your respects. - Fuck you   Seth.
走 去見開曼
Let's go talk to Cameron   Danny.
- 溫亞教父? - 派對如何? 我叫傑森 這是克奡
- Father Vinyard? - How's it going? l'm Jason   this is Chris.
- 我們是你弟弟的朋友 - 你真是上帝!
- We're friends with your brother. - You are a fucking god   man!
- 媽的 說得好 - 德瑞!
- Oh   shit   yeah. - Derek!
- 我以為你交了那報告 - 對...
- I thought you turned that paper in. - I did...
...莫瑞去告狀...
...and now fucking Murray turned me in...
...西尼要我重寫別的
...and so Sweeney's making me write another one.
老西尼真是永不放棄 是嗎?
Good old Sweeney. He never stops trying   now   does he?
他以黑人為傲 我最恨這種人
He's one of those proud-to-be-nigger people. l hate those guys.
不 丹尼
Now   wait a minute   Danny.
他不是驕傲
He's not proud.
是自以為很神的湯姆叔叔
He's a manipulative   self-righteous Uncle Tom.
想讓你覺得寫希特勒很罪惡
He's trying to make you feel guilty about writing about Adolf Hitler. Yeah.
有些黑人 拉丁美洲人 寫寫馬丁·路德金...
Some nigger   some spic writes about Martin Luther King...
...寫寫凱薩·恰瓦茲...
...or fucking Cesar "Commie" Chavez...
...就能得獎
...gets a pat on the head.
很偽善吧?
I mean   you can see the hypocrisy in that   can't you?
當然
Definitely.
來嘛 快點嘛
Come on   let's go. Let's go.
聽我說
No   listen to me.
我很想見你 真的 但今晚先要處理點事
I wanna see you   okay? I do. But l gotta take care of something tonight.
- 好吧 - 能了解嗎?
- Okay. - You understand?
我都在這 等你弄完
Yeah. l'm here. When you're ready   l'm here.
- 願跟我做件事嗎? - 任何事
- Look   would you do something with me? - Anything.
跟我離開
Leave with me.
- 離開哪? - 離開這一切
- Leave where? - Leave here. Leave all this.
跟我一起走
Just come with me.
幹嘛離開? 他們膜拜你 你是他們的神
Why would you wanna Ieave? They worship you. You're like a god to them.
以前那算什麼 ...
If you think we had it good before...
- ...現在才正點 - 我都不要了
- ...wait till you see what it's like now. - I don't want all that.
我不要再牽連家人了 我已經連累家堣H夠多了
I don't want my family involved. Everything I've done here has fucked it up.
- 你懂嗎? - 你覺得錯了?
- Do you understand? - You think what you did was wrong?
少來
Oh   baby. Oh   come on.
那些黑鬼罪有應得...
Those niggers got exactly what they deserved...
...大家心知肚明
...and we all know that.
我知道你剛出來...
I understand you just got out...
但沒人敢傷你 沒人敢動你
...but no one's gonna hurt you. No one can touch you.
外面有一支軍隊
There's a small army out there.
黑鬼絕別想占便宜
We won't let a bunch of spooks kick us out of here.
你沒聽懂 我不是怕
Stacey   you're not Iistening to me   okay? I'm not scared.
我是不要了
I don't want it anymore.
我不想再搞這事了
I'm done with it. l'm through with this.
全....
It's....
全是狗屎
It's bullshit   Stacey.
那不是你要的 相信我
listen   you don't need this   Stacey. Come on   trust me.
想和我在一起 就相信我 跟我走
If you wanna be with me   just trust me. Come with me.
好嗎
Come on.
你瘋了
You're nuts.
你瘋了 我不走
You are nuts. No way.
你不知道現在這堛漯洩p
I don't think you realize what's been going on here.
我們比以前大十倍 而且有組織
We are 10 times what we were   and we are bloody organized.
你絕對想不到!
I mean   it is like nothing you have ever seen!
我錯了 算了
This is a mistake. Forget it.
等等 什麼錯了?
Wait a second. Wait a second. What was a mistake?
史黛西 說再見吧
Stacey   just say goodbye. Just say goodbye.
這不像你
This isn't you.
- 我了解你 - 你根本不懂我
- I know you. - You don't know anything about me   Stacey.
- 你是丹尼他哥? - 是的
- Hey. Are you Danny's brother? - Yeah.
告訴他麗絲找他
Tell him Lizzy's looking for him.
麗絲 請你轉告
Lizzy. Thank you.
讓黑鬼 拉丁鬼來分嘛
We'll let the niggers   kikes and spics grab for their piece of the pie.
難怪他們
Can't blame them.
但他們得贏 才分的到
Of course   they're gonna have to fight to get it.
能把他們趕走...
And if we scare the fuck out of people...
...我們若有死傷也值得
...and a few people get kilied in the process   so be it.
要寫下來 丹
You gonna put that in your paper   Danny?
- 嗨 - 這是誰啊
- Ha   ha. Hey   man. - Well   look who's here.
歸鄉的英雄
The return of the soldier.
- 你來幹嘛 丹? - 別這樣 我來看看
- What are you doing here   Danny? - Come on   man. I had to check it out.
- 你知道我會來 - 隨他去吧 德瑞
- You knew l was gonna come. - Let the kid alone   Derek.
他自己會上床
He knows when to go to bed.
- 去外面等 - 拜托 我沒幹嘛
- Go wait outside. - Come on   I'm not doing anything.
有個女孩在外面
There's a little blond sitting out there.
說找你 快急死了 去吧
She keeps asking for you. She's dying. Come on.
- 我去看看 - 對她溫柔點
- Well   l gotta check out. - Go easy on her.
好的
All right.
外面等我
Wait for me right outside.
別緊張
Take it easy.
開心點
Chill out.
這堳雃w全
You're on safe ground.
不必老提心吊膽
You don't have to watch your ass around here.
來 坐 輕松點
Come on   sit down. Relax.
抱歉 急著開派對
I'm sorry. The party was a little quick.
我們太高興你回來了
But we're just so damned glad you're back   Derek.
- 你覺得怪 很正常 - 我不覺的怪
- It's only natural you should feel funny. - I don't feel funny   Cam.
你把胖子嚇了一跳 胖子覺得你坐牢坐壞了
You know   you made the fat kid nervous. He thinks the joint messed with your mind.
是坐壞了
It did.
光榮 光榮 哈婺籊
Glory   glory halielujah
白人勇士上戰場
The white man marches on
你走後 情況不一樣了
Things have changed since you've been gone   Derek.
你說要組織?
You talk about organization?
看過我們網路你就知道
Wait till you see what we've done with the lnternet.
西雅圖到聖地牙哥的幫派 全都集結了
We've got every gang from Seattle to San Diego working together now.
幫派不再競爭 他們團結了
They're not competing. They're consolldated.
我們只缺全盤的領導
Only thing we lack is a little overall leadership.
你來的正是時候
And that's where you come in.
那些人都很尊敬你 德瑞
Because peopIe out there got a lot of respect for you   Derek.
- 你准備好 就告訴我 - 你別作夢了
- When you're ready   talk to me about it. - Well   you can forget about that.
我不玩了 開曼
I'm done with it   Cam.
我知你很早...
Yeah   well   l know you grew out of that...
...就開始留頭發了 謝天謝地
...shaved-head bullshit a long time ago   thank God.
現在這樣很好
I like your hair the way it is now.
我們該做點大事
See   that's what I mean. We're thinking bigger now.
- 別再搞砸店... - 你沒聽懂
- No more of this grocery store... - You're not listening to me.
我受夠了 我不吃你那套狗屎了
I am done with it. All that bullshit out there and all your bullshit too.
不玩了
I'm out.
我了解你在堶惚傶屭...
I understand how you feel. You've just done some hard time...
別跟我說難受
Don't fucking talk to me about hard time.
- 你根本不懂 - 我坐過牢
- You don't know a thing about it. - I done mine.
屁 那是你編的
You didn't do shit. I found out about your story.
坐兩個月 你就叫兩個孩子當替死鬼
You did two months   then rolied over on two kids and let them go down for you.
別再唬我了 開曼!
So don't feed me your fucking Iies   Cameron!
好吧 太蠢了
All right   then. This is stupid.
談不下去了
I'm done.
你去冷靜冷靜
Look   you go cool off. Get Iaid. Do something.
清醒後再來找我
Get your head on straight   then l'll talk to you.
沒有我也沒關系 是嗎?
But it doesn't matter if l don't   does it?
有一堆人替你效命...
You got the next crop all lined up and ready to go...
- ...老狐狸! - 什麼?
- ...you fucking chicken hawk! - Excuse me?
你捉小雞來利用!
You prey on peopIe   Cam! You use them!
你的謊言害我坐三年牢...
I lost three years of my life for your fucking phony cause...
...看穿你了 蛇精
...but l am onto you   you fucking snake.
德瑞 嘴巴幹淨點
Hey   Derek. Watch it. Be careful.
看看這是誰的地盤
Remember where you are.
這不是能隨意進出的小酒吧...
This is not a fucking country club where you can waltz in and out of here...
閉上狗嘴!
Shut up! Shut the fuck up!
我是來告訴你: 我不玩了!
I came in here to tell you one thing: I am out. Out!
丹尼也是
And Danny is out too.
敢靠近我家人 我會殺你
You come near my family again   I'll fucking kill you.
抱歉 操你的 德瑞
Well   excuse me   but fuck you   Derek.
想嚇唬我 還早
You can't come barking threats at me.
你要走請便 但丹尼是乖孩子
You can do whatever you want   but Danny is a good kid.
他不像你膽小 他需要我幫助
He's not some whining pussy like you. He needs my help and l'll give it to him.
敢靠近丹尼...
If you come near Danny again...
...我會把你的心挖出來
...l will feed you your fucking heart   Cameron.
我不必靠近
I won't have to.
他會來找我
He'll come to me.
你比不上我對他的重要
I'm more important to him now than you'll ever be.
媽的!
Shit!
你死定了 溫亞
You're a fucking dead man   Vinyard.
開曼呢?
Hey   hey   hey. Where's Cameron?
他人呢?
Where the fuck is he?
- 德瑞 - 德瑞
- Hey   Derek. - Hey   Derek.
別來 史黛西 丹尼!
Stay away from me   Stacey. Danny!
告訴他們你剛說的話...
Why don't you share what you just said to me...
...宣揚種族平等的黑鬼!
...you piece-of-shit   race-trading nigger!
- 黑鬼痞子? - 你個不要臉的叛徒!
- Fucking nigger? - You monkey-fucking traitor!
你是黑鬼?
Are you a fucking nigger?
丹尼! 過來
Hey   Danny! Come on.
黑鬼痞子 黑鬼 黑鬼
He's a fucking nigger. Nigger. Nigger.
開曼昏了!
Cam's out cold!
你想去哪?
Where the fuck are you going?
他有槍!
He's got a gun!
退後 退後 塞斯
Yo   yo   back up   back up. Seth.
你讓我想吐!
You make me fucking sick!
塞斯! 把槍放下!
Seth! Put down the fucking gun!
開槍
Go ahead. Shoot.
開槍! 塞斯 開槍
Shoot him! Do it   Seth! Shoot him! Seth. Holy shit.
- 叛徒 - 宰了他
- Traitor. - Kick his ass.
- 塞斯! - 塞斯 開槍
- Seth! - Do it   Seth   do it.
- 開槍 - 開槍!
- Shoot him. - Do it! Shoot him!
天啊
Oh   God.
退後 快
Back up. Move.
退後 給我退後
Back up. Back up. Back the fuck up.
快
Move. Move.
冷靜 德瑞
Easy   Derek. Hey. Hey.
- 丹尼 冷靜 - 操你 你以為你是誰?
- Danny   easy. - Fuck you. Who do you think you are?
丹尼 冷靜
Danny   Danny. Relax. Relax.
- 你以為你是誰啊? - 丹尼 冷靜點
- Who do you think you are? - Danny. Take it easy   Dan. Take it easy.
我他媽的恨你 德瑞!
I fucking hate you   Der!
我知道 好了
All right. Shh   shh. I mean it.
好了 別說了
Hey   come on. Come on. Shut up. Shut up.
- 冷靜點 - 你怎麼了 德?
- Take it easy. - What's happened to you   Der?
冷靜點
Take it easy. Take it easy.
你怎麼了 德?
What's happened to you   Der?
過來
Come on. Come on.
真他媽的幹
This is so fucked.
我很抱歉 你明白嗎?
Look. l'm sorry. All right?
你不該看見的 我叫你別去
You weren't supposed to see that. I told you not to come.
我操你
Fuck you   man.
真他媽丟臉
That was so fucked up.
我知道
I know. I know.
- 天啊 - 不該那樣的
- God. - It wasn't supposed to happen that way.
真搞砸了
That was fucked up.
- 搞得天翻地覆 - 我沒計劃那樣
- That's all there is to it. - Not what l had planned.
發生太快了
It just all went to shit.
全搞砸了
It went to shit.
完全失控
Totally out of control.
你到底怎麼了?
What's fucking happening to you   man?
看著我
Hey. Look at me.
我不能回去了
I can't go back to that   Dan.
不能回哪堨h?
Can't go back to what?
那些人 幫派 那種生活 我不能再過了
To any of it. Those guys   the gang   that life. I'm done with it.
你出了什麼事?
What happened to you up there?
C排 吃飯了 混蛋 今天別遲到!
C Block! Back at the chow! Don't be late today   you piece of shit!
快 要不要吃?
Let's go! You wanna eat today?
五分鍾內起來!
Get up! Five minutes!
這是我地盤 起來!
This is my fucking house! Get up!
你有病啊 混蛋?
What the fuck's your problem   you asshole?
快走!
Move!
喬 開門
Joe   open the fucking gates.
好 退後
All right   back up.
五分鍾內 往前站成一排
Five minutes. Step forward.
給我把床整好
Those beds better be made.
呆在那堣~兩天 我就覺得一星期後就完了
After two days in that place   I didn't think I'd make it a week.
快點 混蛋
Come on there   motherfuckers.
想不想吃啊 爛貨?
You wanna eat today   you piece of shit?
死白雞 你以為你很特別?
You white-trash piece of shit. You think you're fucking special?
扣子扣好 走了 快!
Button that top button. Let's go! Move!
你在瞪我? 別瞪我
Are you fucking eyeballing me? Don't eyeball-fuck me   asshole.
我會斃了你
I'll fucking kill you.
我會注意你 死白雞
Fucking keep my eye on you   you white piece of shit.
別瞪我 不然我操死你!
Don't fucking eyeball me   boy   or l'll fucking skull-fuck you!
往前站
Step forward.
向左轉
Turn to the left.
往前走去吃飯 快
Step forward to chow. Let's go.
快
Come on.
白雞 跟著走
Hey   fish   straight ahead. Straight ahead   fucker.
快
Let's go.
其他犯人都知道我幹的事...
All the wrong people knew who I was anyway...
...我只好想辦法找同伴
...so I figured I'm just gonna put up a flag and hope a friend sees it.
這就是那個新來的
That's the catapult right there.
- 你好嗎? - 還好
- How you doing? - Good.
請坐
Have a seat.
- 我是史派 幸會 - 嗨
- Spike. Good to meet you. - Hey.
別惹我 我是這堻怌ㄘう漱H
Don't fuck with me   all right? Because I'm the most dangerous man in this prison.
知道為什麼?
You know why?
因為我控制內褲
Because I control the underwear.
從這堮釣 到那邊分類
All right   we pick them up over here and we sort them over there.
你最好認真點 上次派來的那人...
I hope you work out   all right? The last guy they sent me...
...沒穿過內褲 號碼都不會分...
...didn't wear no drawers   couldn't read the sizes in the drawers...
...只愛聞內褲
...and used to sniff the drawers.
號碼有兩個: 中和大 明白嗎?
We got two sizes: medium and large. All right?
只要把中的歸中...
All you do is put the mediums with the mediums...
...大的歸大
...and the large with the large.
很無聊 但總比在廚房好
It's a boring job   but it's better than that last shit they had me doing.
我在那待了兩年 整天洗那些臭鍋
I spent two years in the kitchen   ha   scrubbing hot-ass pots and pans.
你不會喜歡那差事的
That   you don't wanna do. All right?
你該高興被派到這
You should be happy that you landed this job.
別的爛差事一堆
Ain't no tellng what the hell they'll have you do in the joint.
順便問下...
By the way   uh...
...你犯了什麼罪進來的?
...what are you in for?
搶了老太太?
Probably robbed some old lady   huh?
我知道你是哪種人
Okay   l know your kind   right?
暴躁的窮白鬼
Badass peckerwood with an attitude.
我告訴你
Well   let me tell you something   man.
你最好小心點
You better watch your ass.
在牢...
Because in the joint...
...黑鬼是你 不是我
...you the nigger   not me.
一年後 我覺得很安全了
l was a year in. I thought I was cruising.
情況卻越來越複雜
Then everything started getting complicated.
我來搞定
I'll take care of that   all right?
那在幹嘛?
What the fuck is that?
搞什麼鬼?
What's that all about?
那是政治 給好處
Oh   that's just politics   man. Favors   you know.
他給拉丁豬好處?
He's doing favors for that fucking spic?
米奇跟他們私下有點生意
Mitch has got a little something extra on the side with them boys   you know.
你騙我 對吧?
You're kidding   right?
沒有
No.
真是狗屎 該跟他說一下
That's bullshit   man. Somebody should say something to him.
他腦子壞啦?
What the fuck is he thinking?
你活到今天全靠米奇
Mitch is the only reason why you're not a corpse right now.
- 別忘了 - 我可不在乎
- Remember that. - You know what? l don't fucking give a shit.
我能靠自己 他不該做那事
I can take care of myself. He shouldn't be doing that.
我要吐了 說牢埵h恐怖...
I'm getting sick of it. A lot of hard talk around here...
...根本是鬼扯
...and not a lot of follow-through.
你最好別太激動...
I think you'd better chill out...
...嘴巴幹淨點 我受夠你那套了
...on the preaching bullshit   okay? We're getting a little tired of that shit.
安分點
Ease up on it.
你來幹嘛 媽?
What are you doing here   Doris?
我在附近
I was in the neighborhood.
叫你們別來看我
Well   look   I told you I don't want you all coming here.
我管不了了
I don't care what you told me   okay?
我有事找你
I need to talk to you now.
你們都好嗎?
So how is everyone?
戴薇娜很棒 功課都是A
Davina's great. She's   uh   getting straight A's almost.
愛莉會走了...
And   uh   Ally's walking...
...會說一點話
...and starting to talk a little.
- 丹尼呢? - 丹尼?
- How's Danny? - Danny?
丹尼
Danny.
丹尼他好崇拜你
He holds you up so high.
他把你當神
He thinks you're the greatest.
常在開曼和朋友面前...
He's always bragging about you to Cameron...
...誇贊你
...and all his new friends.
他讓我想到你
He's starting to remind me of you.
老天 別那麼擔心
Jesus   don't sound so worried   all right?
他沒事的
I'm sure he's fine.
他16歲了 不會永遠是個小天使
I mean   he's 16 years old   Doris. He's not gonna be a little angel forever.
我看見大兒子毀了一生...
You think because l watched my first-born fuck up his entire life...
...能讓小兒子也步他後塵嗎?
...that l can sit here and see my baby follow him down the same toliet?
我在坐牢 能怎辦? 別拿這煩我
You know what? I can't fix all this shit from up here   okay?
沒要你怎辦
I'm not asking you to.
我待在這夠苦 你還過來折磨我
It makes me feel bad. I'm trying to get through this   you make it harder.
只有你苦嗎 德瑞?
You think you're the only one doing time   Derek?
你一個人受苦?
You think you're here all alone?
你在這 我會好過?
You think I'm not in here with you?
操
Fuck   man.
這樣搞床單 就以為搞得完?
Every day you go through these sheets like you gonna get to the end of them.
黑鬼 別板個臉
Look   nigga   will you chill the fuck out?
媽的! 不管你做多快...
Goddamn! No matter how fast you get through them   man...
...他們還是會不斷送來
...they'll keep bringing them in and bringing them in.
用丟的只會害你心髒病
Throwing them around ain't gonna do a thing but give you a heart attack.
我是無所謂
Know what? That's cool with me.
但我也快被你嚇出心髒病了!
But you're gonna give me a goddamn heart attack too!
我知道 我是蠢黑鬼
I know   I know. I'm just a dumb stupid nigger   right?
我懂個屁?
What do I know?
但我不會拿床單出氣
I know l ain't the one getting mad at them damn sheets   though.
會讓我生氣的 是這個:
As a matter of fact   the only sheets I get mad at? I'll tell you.
"各位 這麼辦
"Boys   this is what we gonna do.
今天我們來恨黑鬼
We gonna hate some niggers.
大家恨黑鬼 恨黑鬼一天
We gonna hate some goddamn niggers. That's all we'll do   is hate niggers all day.
還沒想到恨哪個 隨便恨
I don't know what a nigger is   but we'll hate them.
我表弟德瑞在牢...
My cousin Derek is in the pen right now...
...跟一個黑鬼工作 快被搞瘋了"
...working next to a nigger   driving him nigger crazy."
你看 這才像話
See? That's the ticket.
好好做
Nice and easy.
井水不犯河水
Now we can ignore each other in peace.
我說 "你在幹嘛?" 知道他告訴我什麼?
I go   "What you doing?" Know what he tells me?
他說: "我想操的那豬更爛"
He goes   "lt's better than the pig I just tried to fuck."
都不讓我說完
Never lets me finish.
- 說個笑話吧? - 你也操了他?
- Why don't you tell a joke? - Did you fuck him too?
我回去 她躺著 她喜歡用啤酒瓶搞自己
I get back   she's laying on her back. She Iikes the wine bottIe thing   right?
怎麼了?
What's up?
講重點好嗎? 老天
Will you get to the fucking point? Jesus Christ.
他向墨西哥人買貨 賣自己人
He was taking it from the Mexicans and dealing it out to his own people.
那些人完全沒有良知
He didn't believe in shit. None of them did.
花了太長時間
Took too damn long.
溫亞!
Hey. Hey   Vinyard!
幹嘛?
What?
別那樣看我
Come on   man. Don't look at me like that.
知道這味道吧?
You know what that smells like   right?
這會讓人想起女人
Come on   don't tell me this smell doesn't remind you of a woman.
真想念那味道
God   I miss that smell   man.
我在外面的工作也沒多好
The job l had on the outside wasn't much better than this one.
但至少回家都能躺在這味道旁
But at least l gotta go home at night and lie down next to this sweet smell.
天哪 想死了
God   I miss that.
你有女人嗎?
You got a woman?
你一定有女人
Yeah   you got a woman   man.
給你一些忠告
Let me give you some advice. All right?
如果她來看你...
She comes to visit you...
...無論如何 在她離開前千萬別吵架
...whatever you do   no matter what   don't Iet her leave here in a fight.
別讓她走時心情不好...
Don't let her walk out of here with a bad attitude. If you do...
...否則你每天都會擔心 她會去找別人上床
...you spend next week wondering if she's getting her fuck on with somebody eIse.
所以她來時 跟她說些好聽的
She comes to see you it's nothing but sweet talk through that gIass.
讓她開心的離開
Send her away floating   all right?
這堣ㄨ野~面 你可以跟她吵...
Because it's not like the real world. Where you can fight...
...吵完再來個"補償性"做愛
...but it's cooI to fight because you can make up and have make-up sex.
你知道的 憤怒做愛 邊氣邊做愛
You know what l'm saying? That angry sex. That sex with an attitude.
你可以背朝天 讓她打你 把氣發出來
Where you lay on your back and let her take out all that aggression on you.
男人都知道 很刺激的做愛
All guys know that   man. That's that good sex.
嘰嘰叫
It's that pow   pow   pow.
她先在上面處罰你
Let her get on top and she's gonna punish you first   right?
"你好壞
"You been a bad boy   huh?
壞孩子 我打你
You been a bad boy and l'm gonna punish you.
我打你屁屁 別再讓我看見你...
I'm gonna put it on you. Don't you ever let me catch you...
...偷看別的女生
...looking at another woman.
讓我爽我就饒了你
Yeah. l may forgive you if you bring it.
好像快來了 我原諒你
I think I can. I forgive.
我原諒你 就是那 你戳到了
I forgive. Oh   right there. Right there. You hitting it. My spot.
就是那 爽 爽 我原諒你了
That's it. Right. Yeah. Yeah. Yes. l forgive you.
我原諒你了 我原... 我原... 我原諒你了
I forgive you. I for... l for... I forgive you.
我愛你!"
I love you!"
動起來
Let's keep it moving.
湖人隊怎會比塞爾提克更強?
How do you figure the Lakers to ever be a bigger dynasty than the Celtics?
- 湖人只是僥幸 - 你瘋啦?
- The Lakers are like a flare-up. A fluke. - Are you crazy?
四年一遇的好教練 塞爾提克才是傳奇!
One good coach for four years. The Celtics are like a dynasty!
少來  塞爾提克是史上最醜的隊
Come on   man. The Celtics were   like   the ugliest team in the history of sports.
最醜的傳奇
A dynasty of ugly motherfuckers   man.
那個凱文麥豪
Look at Kevin McHale.
詹姆渥西的頭像西瓜
James Worthy? The guy has a head like a melon.
- 女人愛他 - 真沒辦法跟你說話
- No   he had ladies. - I can't even taIk to you.
- 我都不知道你在說什麼 - 你頭殼壞了
- I don't even know what you're saying. - You are tweaking.
波士頓 塞爾提克
Boston Celtics.
- 幾條了? - 夠了
- How many is that? - That's enough.
夠了? 好的
Enough? All right.
我算糊塗了
I lost count   man.
- 沒關系 - 好的
- Doesn't matter   man. - All right.
誰會來算?
Who's counting anyway?
我問你
All right   so l wanna know something.
你怎麼進來的?
What the fuck landed you in here?
沒殺人 又沒混幫派
You didn't kill. Too skinny for a gangbanger.
什麼話 別光看我瘦 我也有拳頭 懂嗎?
That a bitch. Don't judge a book by its cover. l can throw these things   all right?
- 你懂嗎? - 好啦 到底怎樣嘛?
- You know what l'm saying? - Whatever. Come on. What did you do?
不幹你事 太丟臉了
Yo   man   it's none of your business   all right? lt's embarrassing   all right?
什麼? 丟臉...? 誰不丟臉
What? Embar...? Everybody in here is embarrassed.
進來的人都是沒跑掉
You think? Nobody in here got away with anything.
做了什麼嘛?
What did you do?
我偷了電視
Look   man   I stole a TV   all right?
偷電視怎會丟臉?
So you stole a TV. What's embarrassing?
我偷了電視 隔壁是早餐店
I stole a TV from a store that was right next door to a doughnut shop   all right?
我跑 老板邊追邊叫
I run out   the store owner's running behind me   yelling   bam.
我撞到三個條子
I run into three cops   all right?
看吧 我說了丟臉 你笑我
I told you it was embarrassing and you laugh.
等一下
Wait a second. Wait a second.
那沒道理啊
That doesn't make sense.
偷電視怎會判六年?
No   you didn't get six years for stealing a TV.
- 老實交代 - 我跑進店 跑出來...
- Come on. - I go in the store   l come out...
...條子捉我手 電視砸到他腳
...the police officer grabs my arm   TV falls on his foot and breaks it.
他們說我拿電視砸警察
They said I threw the TV at the officer.
襲警罪 判了六年
Assault. Six years.
說實話
Come on. Tell the truth.
你是砸他或怎樣
You chucked it at him. Or something.
我說了 我從店媔]出來...
like l said   l came out of the store...
...他抓我 電視機就掉到他腳上
...he grabbed my arm   it fell on his foot.
你很行嗎 寶貝? 你很行嗎 你很行嗎?
What you got for me   baby? What you got for me? What you got for me?
射一個
There you go   baby. Yeah   baby.
這才叫帥!
That's what l'm talking about!
防住他
Put some D on him   now.
操你
Fuck you.
拿毛巾來! 抓住他
Get a towel! Hold him. Hold him.
- 想當黑鬼 寶貝? - 操你!
- You wanna be a nigger   sweet boy? - Fuck you!
就把你當黑鬼
We're gonna treat you like one.
加油
Come on.
操你
Fuck you.
- 搞的真爽  - 操你!
- That was real sweet. - Fuck you!
(白人強權)
他怎樣?
How is he?
縫了六針
Well   he took six stitches.
嘿 老兄
Hey   man.
你到底是來幹嘛?
Oh   man   what the hell are you doing here   anyway?
想談談丹尼 待會再說
Well   I came to talk about Danny   but we don't have to do that right now.
給你幾本書
I brought you some books.
他怎麼了? 別吊我胃口
Well   what about him? You know? Don't keep me in suspense.
他正在步你後塵
He's headed right where you are.
我媽已經來探望過我了
Oh   man   you know what? My mother already laid this trip on me   man.
丹尼不是我責任
Danny's not my responsibility. You know?
我能怎麼辦? 想也沒用 要我自責嗎?
What do you expect me to do? It doesn't heIp. Am I supposed to feel guilty?
沒要你幹嘛 我只想知道你的感覺
I don't want you to do anything. l need to know the truth about how you feel.
我會希望他進來嗎? 我的意思是....
Well   what? You think I want him in here? I mean....
我不知道我什麼感覺...
I don't know. l don't know what I feel. I'm all....
我覺得很迷惑
I feel a little inside out.
我不知道 有些事...
Um   you know   I don't know. There's some things...
...跟我想的不一樣
...that don't fit.
常有的事
Well   that happens.
你這麼聰明 不該淪落至此...
Look   you are too damn smart to be floating around here...
...不會看不清那種假象
...pretending you don't see the holes in this bullshit.
我是迷惑 但沒說不相信
listen   I said l was confused. I didn't say I didn't believe in it.
你得敞開心胸
All right. That's why you have to stay open.
憤怒在征服你
Right now   your anger is consuming you.
憤怒把你腦袋沖昏了
Your anger is shutting down the brain God gave you.
從高中你就一直談我的內心
You've been talking about what's going on in me since l was in high school.
你怎會知道我心媟Q什麼?
How the fuck do you know so much about what's going on inside me?
我了解我自己
No   I know about me.
了解這 了解你待在什麼地方
I know about this place. I know about the place you are in.
你知道這堣偵?
What do you know about the place l'm in?
有一陣子...
There was a moment...
...我怪罪一切 怪每個人...
...when I used to blame everything and everyone...
...讓我和我的同胞...
...for all the pain and suffering and vile things that happened to me...
...受盡痛苦折磨
...that l saw happen to my people.
我怪每個人 怪白人
I used to blame everybody. Blame white people.
怪社會 怪上帝
Blame society. Blame God.
他不回答 是因為我問的不對
I didn't get no answers   because I was asking the wrong questions.
- 你要問對問題 - 例如什麼?
- You have to ask the right questions. - like what?
你曾努力讓你人生更好嗎?
Has anything you've done made your life better?
沒有
No.
你要幫我
You gotta help me now.
幫幫我
Just help me.
把我弄出去
Get me out of here   you know?
我還剩四個月就面試
I'm up in four months for review.
幫我說說好話
Put in a word for me.
我已經說了好話 那你出去後呢?
I already have. So you're out there   then what?
我不要讓家人再擔心
I don't wanna fuck up my family anymore.
我要離的遠遠的
I'll go as far away as l can get.
那還不夠
That's not good enough.
要我幫你 就得更努力 我是有條件的
You want my heIp   you gotta do better than that. My help is not unconditional.
逃避不是好辦法
But running just ain't good enough.
操他
Fuck him.
操他 讓他去當黑鬼啊
Fuck him. Fuck him. Let the niggers have him.
怎樣 德?
Yo   what's up   D?
你在餐廳做了什麼事?
Yo   what's all that bullshit you pulied in the mess hall   man?
你頭殼壞啦 瘋啦?
Are you out of your fucking mind? Are you fucking crazy?
德 看著我!
D! Look at me   man!
你不能一個人扛著
You can't make it on your own.
我不怕那些婊子 那次六個人攻我
I'm not afraid of those fucking pussies. There was six of them   they jumped me.
沒下次了 他們敢來就再來
That won't happen again. I hope they fucking try.
我不是說你的白人朋友!
Look   l'm not talking about your peckerwood friends!
他們保護你!
They were protecting your stupid ass!
你還公然挑釁
You dissed them in public.
現在沒人靠了!
Now you're on your fucking own!
小心我那幫兄弟
Yo   man   l'm talking about the brothers.
他們會操你 扁你 宰了你!
They're gonna fuck you   toss your salad   then smoke your motherfucking ass!
說點我不知道的吧  你以為我沒想過?
Tell me something l don't already know. You think I haven't thought about that?
要來就讓他們來 我無能為力
They're gonna come for me   they're gonna come. Nothing I can do.
我能怎樣?
What can I do   man?
我又回到以前
So I was right back where I started.
每天都想: 他們要來了
Every day   I was sure it was my day.
每當我走出牢房時
Every time I stepped out of my cell.
每當我進那浴室時
Every time I got in that shower.
我想他們有所行動是遲早的事
I figured it was only a matter of time before they made a move.
我只希望快點來臨
I just hoped that it'd be quick.
但他們沒有再來
But it never came.
我猜不透 我知道有人很想扁我
I couldn't figure it out. I knew some of them were itching for it.
之後 我就獨來獨往...
But after a while l just put my head down...
...埋頭去讀西尼給我的那些書
...read the stuff that Sweeney sent me   and I kept to myself.
最後那六個月 我像個鬼魂
The last six months in that place I was like a ghost.
怎樣? 要出去啦?
What's up   man? You getting out?
還等什麼? 快滾啊
What the fuck you waiting on? Get the fuck on out of here.
- 我有個奇怪感覺 - 什麼?
- Yeah   you know   I got this funny feeling. - Oh   yeah? What's that?
我覺得我能平安離開是因為你
I'm thinking maybe the only reason I'm getting out of here in one piece is you.
少來 快滾吧 你!
Come on   man. Get the fuck out of here   man!
我會為白雞拼自己老命?
You think I'm gonna put my neck on the line for a crazy-ass peckerwood?
對 我是白癡
Yeah. Right. Stupid.
我是這麼猜想
That's what l thought.
我欠你
I owe you   man.
你欠我個屁
Man   you don't owe me shit   all right?
我欠你
Yes   l do.
你也快走了
You'll be out in no time.
放心 小意思
Come on   man. It's a piece of cake. All right?
小心那些兄弟 小心點!
You just take it easy on the brothers   all right? The brothers!
天哪
God   man.
我很難過 德
I'm sorry   Der.
你的那些事
Sorry that happened to you.
我不難過 我很幸運
No   I'm not. I'm lucky.
因為我知道...
I feel Iucky because...
...那些是錯的 丹
...it's wrong   Dan.
它啃噬了我 幾乎害我送命
It's wrong and it was eating me up. It was gonna kill me.
我不斷問自己...
And l kept asking myself all the time...
...當初怎會相信那些的?
...how did I buy into this shit   you know?
是因為氣憤
And it's just because I was pissed off.
我做的一切都沒趕走憤恨
And nothing l ever did ever took that feeling away.
丹尼 我殺了兩個人哪
I mean   l killed two guys   Danny. I killed them.
但還是沒覺得平靜
And that didn't make me feel any different.
只是更迷失 我覺得好膩
It just got me more lost. And l'm tired of feeling pissed off   Danny.
讓我好厭倦
I'm just tired of it.
我不是要你做什麼
And l'm not telling you what to do.
真的不是
I'm really not.
但我需要你了解
But l need you to understand.
因為我愛你 你是我最好的朋友
Because I love you and you're my best friend.
你了解嗎?
Do you understand?
我了解
Yeah   l understand.
好了
All right.
天哪
Jesus.
- 沒事吧? - 都很好
- Everything okay? - No   everything's great.
你想睡我們的房媔?
Great. Yeah. You wanna sIeep in our room?
- 不了 謝謝 這堳雃n  - 真的?
- No   thank you. Yeah. This is good. l'm fine. - You sure?
謝謝你
Thank you   though.
我們走吧
All right. Come on   let's go.
晚安
Good night.
我去洗個澡
I'm gonna take a shower   all right?
去回想你親人的那些事 真的很痛苦
It's hard to look back and see the truth about people you love.
若問德瑞那些事是始於何時...
I think if you asked Derek why it all went the way it did   and where it all started...
...他可能會說 是爸被謀殺後
...he'd still say it started when our father was murdered.
但其實是更早以前
But the truth is   it started earlier.
晚上一起去看球賽嗎?
All right. Are we all meeting together for the game tonight?
當然
Yes   definitely.
地點在本伯格 七點集合 看帥哥打球
Ben's Burgers   7:00   then we go watch the big guy play.
好的
Okay. Yeah.
- 心埵陪蒬ぃa? - 一直都有
- Psyching up for the game? - Yeah   I'm always ready for that.
要考英文 有點緊張 我還沒准備好
I got an English exam third period. I'm having a heart attack. I'm not ready.
怎麼 怕考個B?
What's the matter   afraid you're gonna get a B?
B減也無所謂
Might do you good. B minus.
別笑我 他真的不一樣
Don't laugh. This guy is different.
西尼博士太神了 我沒碰過這種老師
Dr. Sweeney? This guy's unbelievable. I've never had a teacher like this.
是雙學位博士 竟然來教我們
He's got two Ph.D.s. I don't know what he's doing at our school.
- 他跟其他老師不同 - 叫你念什麼?
- He's not like other teachers. - What's he got you reading?
我們要考"土著"這本書
We got this essay exam on this book   Native Son.
- 以它出題 - "土著" 我沒聽過
- All on this one book. - Native Son. l don't know that.
真是大新聞
That's a big surprise.
我有念書啊
What? l read.
老公 學校不教曆險小說
Honey   they don't teach Tom Clancy at school.
學校不教那個
Well   they don't.
"土著"寫些什麼?
So   what is it? What is this Native Son? What is it?
寫一個黑人的事
It's this book about this black guy.
我們在上黑人文學專輯
We're doing this whole bIack literature unit.
黑人曆史月啊?
What is it   Black History Month?
不是...
No   it's just like...
西尼決定的 讓我們學這個
This guy Sweeney   you know   it's part of the course now.
怎樣?
What?
沒有 只是...
Nothing. It's just   you know.
現在到處都是了
It's everywhere l look now.
什麼?
What?
都在搞"黑人認同運動"
This affirmative blaction.
幾本書搞不了什麼運動
Honey   a few new books doesn't qualify as affirmative black action.
念歸念 考歸考
Read the book   ace the guy's test.
他說的別全都當真
Just don't swallow everything he feeds you whole.
- 像新聞說的... - 什麼?
- Just because you see it on the news. - But like what?
什麼一切平等 哪那麼簡單
All this stuff about making everything equal. It's not that simple.
你現在念這本"土著"
Now you got this book   Native Son.
這門課其他的書呢?
What happened to the other books in the course?
雙學位博士說其他書不好 就不必讀了?
They're not any good anymore because Mr. Two-Ph.D.s says they aren't?
念黑人書 不念好書 合理嗎?
Are you gonna trade in great books for black books? Does that make sense?
你得想想這個
You gotta question these things   Derek.
你要看清真相
You gotta look at the whole picture.
不只這個 我的工作也是
We're taIking about books here. But l'm also talking about my job.
我隊上來兩個黑人...
I got two bIack guys on my squad now who got their job...
...成績較好的白人被擠掉了
...over a couple of white guys who actually scored higher on the test.
這合理嗎? 是 一切都得平等...
That make sense? Huh? Yeah   sure   everything's equal now...
...但我出勤時 這兩個比白人差的人...
...but l got two guys watching my back   responsible for my life...
...要護衛我安全 因是黑人就得做這工作
...who aren't as good as two others. They got the job because they were black.
- 不是能力強 - 好爛
- Not because they were the best. - That sucks.
美國就是這樣嗎?
Yeah. ls that what America is about?
不 美國是"精英職場"
No. America's about "best man for the job."
你能力強 才能有工作
You do your best   you get the job.
這種鬼扯蛋的認同運動...
You know   this affirmative action crap...
我不知道後面...
I don't know what that's about. There's some...
...是不是有什麼陰謀
...hidden agenda or something going on.
- 你懂嗎? - 我懂
- You see what l'm saying? - Yeah   I do.
我沒那麼想過
I don't know   I didn't think about it like that.
- 好的... - 但這個人...
- Well... - This guy   though...
西尼真得很有說服力...
I don't know. Dr. Sweeney   he comes on   like   so strong...
...很難不聽他說
...it's kind of hard not to listen to him.
也許他的話...
Maybe some of what he says is kind of...
都是放屁
It's bullshit.
對 也許
Yeah. Yeah   maybe.
不
No   no.
是放黑屁
It's nigger bullshit.
- 你懂了吧? - 我懂
- You see that   don't you? - Yeah.
- 你要小心 - 我懂 我會小心
- You gotta watch out for that. - Yeah   I get what you're saying. l will.
好孩子
Good boy.
- 我以你為榮 - 放心
- I'm proud of you. - Don't worry about it. l got it.
快淩晨5:40了...
It's 5:40 a.m...
...馬上我要去看日出
...and in about one minute   I'm gonna watch the sun come up.
我忘了有沒有看過日出
I don't know if I've ever done that.
我們得打起精神 重新開始
Anyway   we're gonna try to pick things up and start over.
不是很容易 但我們又團聚了
lt won't be easy   but we're all together again.
我感覺很好
And I feel good.
不知這報告你是否滿意
I'm not sure if this paper is what you wanted.
有無提及你要的社會意義
If I hit the social significance   or whatever you're looking for.
若還有一點價值 得謝謝你
But   for what it's worth   thanks a lot.
氣色真好
Wow. You look great.
你看你
Look at you.
見假釋官得打扮一下
Yeah. Gotta dress up for the parole officer.
是個俏妞?
Is she cute?
是個胖男人
She is a fat guy named Hector.
沒法僥幸了
So l'm out of luck.
跟他報到後 去找工作
I just gotta check in   then l'll see about getting my old job back.
好啊
Great.
早安 小寶貝
Good morning. Yes   my love.
- 黛薇娜 你能...?  - 你姐姐會幫你弄
- Davina   can you...? - Your sister's gonna help you   honey.
好帥 迷死他們
You look great. Knock them dead.
謝了
Thanks.
- 你想要穿什麼? - 我今天想穿藍裙子
- What would you like to wear? - l wanna wear my blue dress today.
- 真好看 - 是嗎? 我覺得很蠢
- You do look good. - Yeah? l feel silly.
- 真得很好 - 是嗎?
- You look good. - Yeah?
心情好嗎?
You feel good?
還好...
Yeah. Yeah. l feel   you know...
...心情有點...
...a little...
我會好的 會的
I'm getting there. I'm getting there.
我不知道...
listen   I don't know...
我不知道能不能讓我留在家
I don't know if it's okay that l'm here.
我想留下
I wanna be here.
- 我去買份報紙 - 好的
- I'm gonna get a paper. - Cool.
- 要什麼? - 蜜餅和牛奶
- What do you want? - A maple bar and a large miIk.
知道了
All right   l got it.
一杯咖啡 蜜餅和牛奶
Let me get a coffee   a maple bar and a large miIk to go.
馬上就來
Right away.
- 德瑞 - 嗨
- Hey   Derek. - Hey.
德瑞
Derek.
- 有事找你 - 怎麼了?
- We need to talk. - What's going on?
開曼和塞斯在聖約翰醫院的加護病房
Cameron Alexander and Seth Ryan are at the lCU at St. John's.
- 他們昨晚被砍了 - 嚴重嗎?
- They were jumped last night. - How bad?
大概死不了
Well   it looks like they're gonna live.
- 算他走運 - 但有人會抓狂
- Then they got lucky. - Somebody's gotta lose   though.
什麼?
Aw   what?
希望你去跟那幫人說說
We were kind of hoping that maybe you'd talk to your old crew.
- 不行 - 暴力不好
- Come on. No way. - This is not a good thing.
他們只可能聽你的
If there's anybody they'll listen to   it's you.
不行 不瞞你說 我已經不玩了
No. No   l hate to tell you   but I'm out.
可能他們倒想砍我
Those guys are probably gunning for me now.
我們是請你幫忙
We're asking for your help here   Derek.
- 你跟他建議的? - 德瑞
- Did you tell him l was gonna do this? - Derek.
那跟我沒關系了
This has got nothing to do with me.
不 有關系 所有一切全都跟你有關系
Yes   it does. It has everything to do with you.
你在幹嘛? 我盡力了
What are you doing to me? You know   I'm doing my best.
我現在好好作人 不想連累家堣H
I'm going like this to keep my family in the cIear.
- 別叫我去解決 - 我沒有
- Don't ask me to fix this. - I'm not asking that.
- 問題早就在了 - 你也有份 現在想逃避?
- It was there before me. - You helped create it. Wanna take a break?
你若逃避 就永遠不會平靜
You take a break   you'll find no peace.
想要平靜只有去阻止
The way to find peace is to stick.
不會有用的
It's not gonna make a fucking bit of difference.
不一定
It might.
你知道這是什麼要求嗎? 你真的知道?
Do you know what you're asking me to do? Do you really know?
我要你想方設法用你的影響力去阻止
Yes. l'm asking you to do whatever is in your power to do.
天啊
Man.
操
Fuck.
好吧
All right.
我會被白人槍殺
You're gonna get me shot by white boys.
- 我想不會 - 好的...
- I doubt it. - Yeah   well...
...那就夠諷刺了
...we're all gonna have a laugh at that   let me tell you.
我帶他去上學 半小時後回來
I'm gonna take him to school. I'll be back in haIf an hour.
過來
Come on.
嗨 東西寫了嗎?
Hey   you. You got something good for me this morning?
- 會給你的 西尼博士 好嗎? - 好的
- I'll give it to you   Dr. Sweeney. All right? - Yeah   okay.
怎麼了?
What's going on?
快走
Come on.
我為塞斯好難過
This is so bad for Seth   man.
- 不知他們的傷重不重 - 不知道
- I wonder how bad they got fucked up. - I don't know.
還好沒死 但我也不在乎
I'm gIad they're not dead   but other than that   I don't care.
要去看他嗎?
Should we visit them?
去看他們? 絕對不要
Visit them? No. No   definitely not.
千萬別管這檔子事
Definitely not. Just stay out of it.
你聽好...
listen   too...
...昨天我離開塞斯那堮 看見有輛車徘徊
...l saw a car cruising by the house last night when l pulled out of there with Seth.
你回到家後 四周看看
If you get home before me   look around the street   all right?
確保一切沒事
Make sure there's nothing going on.
天 真慘
Oh   man. This is bad.
- 他們在找你 - 會沒事的
- They're after you   man. - It'll cool off.
牢房都待過...
If l made it through Chino...
...這小意思
...this should be a piece of cake   right?
- 你會好好的? - 會
- Are you gonna be okay? - Yeah   yeah.
好的
Okay.
你要怎辦?
What are you gonna do?
不知道 會有辦法的
I don't know. l'll work it out. Hey.
精神點 不會有事的
Keep your head up. Things are gonna be fine.
不會有事
It's gonna be fine.
把報告交了
Go turn that paper in.
- 好 再見 - 嘿 丹
- Okay. All right   see you. - Hey   hey   Dan.
家堥
I'll see you at home.
行嗎?
All right?
好 再見
Yeah   I'll see you.
- 祝你好運 - 好的
- Hey   good luck   all right? - Yeah.
再見
See you later.
- 快遲到了 - 快點走
- We're gonna be late. - We'd better go.
- 好的 - 快走
- Okay. - All right. Come on.
- 好的 - 待會去找你
- Fine. - All right. I'll catch up with you   all right?
待會見
See you later.
- 德瑞 不要! - 走開!
- Derek   no! - Get out of my way!
- 冷靜 冷靜 - 走開!
- All right. All right. - Get out of my way!
讓他去!
Let him go!
噢 不 不 不!
Oh   no. No! No! No!
老天啊
Oh   Jesus.
不
No.
噢 不 不 不
Oh   no   no. No.
天啊
Oh   Jesus.
老天啊 我做了什麼?
God   what did I do?
天啊
Oh   God.
我想這就是我學到的
So I guess this is where l tell you what l learned.
我的結論
My conclusion   right?
結論就是...
Well   my conclusion is...
...憎恨是包袱
...hate is baggage.
生命太短暫 不該老發脾氣
life's too short to be pissed off all the time.
根本不值得
It's just not worth it.
德瑞說文章結尾要用名言
Derek says it's always good to end a paper with a quote.
他說 最棒的話已有人說了...
He says someone else has already said it best...
...你超越不了他 就偷他的 來壯大自己
...so if you can't top it   steal from them and go out strong.
所以我選了這段:
So I picked a guy I thought you'd like:
"我們不是敵人 而是朋友
"We are not enemies   but friends.
不要當敵人
We must not be enemies.
盡管會一時沖動...
Though passion may have strained...
...但切勿傷害我們的友愛
...it must not break our bonds of affection.
再相逢時 美好回憶會再度浮現...
The mystic chords of memory will swell when again touched...
...讓他們以更好的角度 看待人類的本質"
...as surely they will be   by the better angels of our nature."